本字幕由 疯狂猪击树 制作
请于下载3小时内删除本作品
在这个角落 ， Roberto Dur á n 。
In this corner, Roberto Durán.
而在这个角落 ， 尔塔斯本尼。
And in this corner, Benny Huertas.
环的技术。
Ring sense is an art.
上帝的礼物 ， 都会像一个斗士的艺术家的绘画。
A gift from God that flows out of a fighter like a painting flows out of an artist.
你就这样从你出生。..
You're either blessed with it from the day you're born...
..or 。你不用骂它 ， 直到你死去。
...or you're cursed without it till you die.
在 66 秒 ， Roberto Dur á n 改变了我的生活。
In 66 seconds, Roberto Durán changed my life.
这是他的
This is his
22 日淘汰赛 25 。
22nd knockout in 25 fights.
你可以让他的冠军。
You can make him a champ.
我知道它。
I know it.
嗯 ， 我不认为我需要你 ， 卡洛斯。
Well, I don't think you need me, Carlos.
我。在孩子的手里了。
I... the kid's got it all.
但他的狂野。
But he's wild.
散漫。
Undisciplined.
你知道 ， 他不能让这个有自己世界锦标赛的冠军。
You know, he can't make this road towards a world championship by himself.
他从小在街头。
He grew up in the streets.
一切战斗 ， 大家。
Fought everything, everybody.
讨厌一切 ， 其中包括美国。
Hates everything, including the United States of America.
包括美国吗 ？
Including the United States?
他的父亲是美国人遗弃他的母亲。
His father was an American who abandoned his mother.
你能帮助他。
You can help him, Ray.
听着 ， 我希望培养的孩子 ， 我只是 … …
Listen, I want to train the kid, I just...
我 - 我不想要你知道.. 。..
I-I don't want... you know...
这不容易。
It's not easy.
我不想闹事。
I don't want to stir things up.
什么 ， 那只 wiseguys ？
What, that thing with the wiseguys?
那是 17 年前。
That was 17 years ago.
- 你觉得他们还在乎吗 ？ - 是啊 ， 是啊。
- Well, you think they still care? - Yeah, yeah.
我可以付给你。
I can pay you under the table.
啊 ， 他们知道所有的技巧。
Ah, they know all the tricks.
我唯一能想到的是。..
The only thing I can think of is...
我训练他的自由。
I'd have to train him for free.
这是个不错的主意。
That's not a bad idea.
好了。
Cholo.
嘿。
Hey.
三十一位和我口味 ！
Thirty-one flavors and I got them all!
我就非常非常重要 ， 我想让你见见。
I got somebody very, very important that I want you to meet.
最好的拳击教练。
The best trainer in the history of boxing.
arcel 射线。
Ray Arcel.
他培训更多的世界冠军 ， 在拳击史上比其他任何人。
He has trained more world champs than anyone else in boxing history.
放松。 别那样看着我。
Relax. Don't look at me like that.
你在哪里 ？
Where are you?
我告诉过你我会带你到麦迪逊广场花园。
I told you I would bring you to the Madison Square Garden.
我已经说过 ， 什么都没发生 ？
Have I ever said anything that didn't happen?
这个人可以让你世界冠军。
This man can make you world champ.
我不需要任何人。
I don't need nobody from America.
我知道。
I know.
我得走了。
I got to go.
嘿 ， 雷 ， 雷 ， 雷 ， 雷。
Hey, Ray, Ray, Ray, Ray.
很高兴见到你 ， 卡洛斯 ， 很新奇。
It's good to see you, Carlos, after all these years.
我们谈谈吧。
We'll talk soon.
谢谢 ， 雷。
Thanks, Ray.
好吧。
Okay.
嘿。
Hey.
你们是怎么搞的 ？
What's wrong with you guys?
这就是雷 arcel
That's Ray Arcel
射线 arcel 。.. 18 锦标赛
Ray Arcel... 18 championships
世界。
of the world.
Qui plomo ？ 。..
Plomo Qui?ones...
虚闪。
cero.
现在你有两个训练师。 你得了巴拿马。 我们的巴拿马。
Now you got two trainers. You got Panama. Our Panama.
和你知道的..
And you got the man who knows...
你真有种 ， eleta 。
You really have balls, Eleta.
我想让你有世界冠军的头衔。 你不想成为世界冠军 ？
I'm trying to make you world champ. You don't wanna be world champ?
那你还吃不吃 ？
You gonna eat all that shit?
当然 ！ 我买了它 ！
Of course! I bought it!
自 1903 年起 ， 运河区是美国控制的领土
Since 1903, the Canal Zone was a U.S.-controlled territory
巴拿马的心脏部位。
right in the heart of Panama.
和火箭的红色眩光。..
And the rockets' red glare...
1964 年 ， 张力达到历史最高水平
By 1964, tension was at an all-time high
巴拿马学生发生冲突 ， 美国在军事
as Panamanian students clashed with the U.S. military over
在悬挂其国旗在自己的土地。
the right to fly their flag in their own land.
巴拿马万岁 ！
Viva Panama!
巴拿马 ！
Panama!
巴拿马 ！ 巴拿马 ！
Panama! Panama!
美国 ！ 美国 ！
USA! USA!
快跑 ！ 快跑 ！
Run! Run!
外面去游泳 ！
Get out there and swim!
游泳对于你的生活 ！
Swim for your life!
在 3 天 ，
The conflict would last for three days,
当一切都结束时 ， 22 名巴拿马人和 4 名美国公民死亡。
and when it was done, 22 Panamanians and four U.S. citizens were dead.
妈妈 ， 这儿有食物!
Mom, got food!
枪声 ， Roberto ， 隐藏在这里 ！
Gun shots, Roberto, hide down here!
你在做什么, 你疯了吗 ？
What are you doing down there, you crazy?
芒果 ！
Mangoes!
等等 ！
Wait!
你偷了吗 ？
Did you steal that?
妈妈 ， 你知道 ， 我根本不需要偷。
Mom, you know me, I don't need to steal.
你在哪找到的 ？
Where did you find that?
我付出我的工作。
I got paid for my work.
谢谢你 ， 儿子。
Thanks, son.
Dur á n 几位老师在他的生命。
Durán had several teachers in his life.
最重要是 chaflan 。
One of the most important was Chaflan.
他喜欢吹笛子的邻域
He was like the Pied Piper of the neighborhood
教孩子们如何生存。
who taught the kids how to survive.
芒果 ！
Mangoes for everyone!
现在大家都说谢谢的芒果。
Now everyone say thanks for the mangoes.
感谢芒果。
Thanks for the mangoes.
如果我是你的球队。
If it's mine it's yours.
如果我们将它送给你。
And if it's ours it's yours.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
左 ， 左 ， 左 ， 右 ， 左。
Left, Left, Left, Right, Left.
Numero DOS ！
Numero dos!
Numero Tres ！
Numero tres!
第四 ！
Numero cuatro!
“Uno ， dos ， tres ， 夸特罗 ！
Uno, dos, tres, cuatro!
快跑 ！ 我们迟到了 ！
Run! We are late!
用你的刺拳。 不要降低你的卫兵。
Use your jab. Don't lower your guard.
爵士。
Sir.
还好吧 ， 孩子 ？
What's up, kid?
你会训练我么 ？
Would you train me?
去上学。 我们在这里工作。
Go to school. We are working here.
你的学校吗 ？
You gonna pay for school?
走吧 ， 孩子。
Just go, kid.
所有的好。
All good.
闭嘴。
Shut up and box.
拳击正在战斗 ， 你要做的是像我的姐妹。
Boxing is fighting, all you do is dance like my sisters.
是啊 ！
Yeah!
你站起来懦夫 ！
Stand up you coward!
我们富有了 ！
We are rich!
我不知道你喜欢打架 ！
I didn't know you liked to fight!
你看到了吗 ？ 我要当世界冠军 ！
You see? I'm gonna be world champ!
然后你要带我到了纽约。
Then you gotta take me to NY.
我们去吃饭吧 ！
Let's go eat!
把钱藏 ！
Hide the money!
把钱给我 ， 孩子。
Give me that money, kid.
把钱给我。
Give me the money.
我没有钱。
I got no money.
他只是个孩子 ！
He's just a kid!
- 嗨 ， 小子 ？ - 这么坏。
- Wassup, kid? - Wassup.
- 一切都好吗 ？ - 是的。
- All good? - Yes.
显然 ， 所有的伟大。
Clearly, all is great.
我可以把你救出来。
I can get you out.
但让我明确一下..
But let me be clear...
如果你正在打架或偷窃。..
If you are caught fighting or stealing...
我会带你离开这里后我和你。
I'll bring you back myself and leave you here.
所以你会训练我么 ？
So you are gonna train me?
他们全部都会被这个不容易。
They're not all gonna be this easy.
有时。..
Sometimes...
你需要点。
You need to get points.
还有技术。..
There's technique...
规则。
Rules.
骗子。
Cheats.
运动。
Movement.
你告诉我你学什么 ？
You learning everything I tell you?
我了解你想要什么..
I learn anything you want...
只要你给我一个冰淇淋。 ．
as long as you get me an ice cream...
每当我杀死这些妓女。
every time I kill one of those fuckers.
你站起来懦夫 ！
Stand up you coward!
嘿。
Hey.
婴儿。
Baby.
转身。
Turn around.
嘿 ， 嘘。
Hey, psst.
布兰迪。
Blondie.
你叫什么名字 ？
What's your name?
小鼠吃了你的舌头 ？
Did the mice eat your tongue?
你不给我你的名字吗 ？
You're not going to give me your name?
嗯 ？
Huh?
你说英语吗 ？
You speak English?
你会说西班牙语吗 ？
You speak Spanish?
幸福
Happiness
你是开玩笑吧 ？ 幸福是你的名字吗 ？
You are kidding me, right? Your name is happiness?
让我猜猜。 这就是你所一直期盼的吗 ？
Let me guess. It's what you've been looking for all your life?
可怜的人生快乐。
The poor are born happy.
富人知道只有悲伤。
Only the rich know sadness.
你还剩下什么
And you still leave?
来这里 ！
Come here!
你要带我去哪里 ？
Where are you taking me?
没关系 ， 我不会咬你。
It's okay, I don't bite.
你们都疯了。
You are nuts.
嫁给我吧 ！
Marry me!
我不认识你 ！
I don't even know you!
正是 ！
Exactly!
我们会在以后的生命中认识彼此。
We'll get the rest of our lives to know each other.
你是真疯了。
You are really crazy.
为你疯狂。
Crazy for you.
我不能改变我是谁。
I can't change who I am.
然后你需要忘记我。
Then you need to forget about me.
你要离开我吗 ？
You're going to leave me here?
你不会忘记我 ！
You're the one who won't forget me!
你会在心中描绘你的笔记本。
You'll be drawing hearts in your notebook.
你 ， 你。..
You are done, you turned...
和你爱上了。
And you fell in love.
你疯了 ！
You're crazy!
What 's up? 那是什么飞船 ？
What's up? What's that spaceship?
老天。他强烈 ！
Jeez. he's intense!
这是卡洛斯 eleta 首富巴拿马。
This is Carlos Eleta, the richest man in Panama.
我找你找了一个小时 ！
I've been looking for you for an hour!
别在大家面前。
Stop screaming in front of everyone.
我想见到你。
I wanted to meet you.
我听说你是无敌的。
I hear you are unbeatable.
小丑你战斗时很容易赢。
When you fight clowns it's easy to win.
你想成为世界拳王 ？ 我可以帮助你。
You wanna be world champ? I can help you.
是的
Yes
你说英语吗 ？
You speak English?
他的长相。
He's looking.
是的 ， 我讲英语。
Yes, I speak English.
你们到麦迪逊广场花园。
Gonna take you to Madison Square Garden.
咱们马上就走。
Let's go right away.
这就是你的飞机吗 ？
This is your plane?
- VAMOS ， VAMOS ， VAMOS 。 - 罗伯特 ， 罗伯特 ， 罗伯特 ，
- Vamos, vamos, vamos. - Robert, Robert, Robert,
罗伯特, 罗伯特, 罗伯特。
Robert, Robert, Robert.
不要看, 不要看。
Don't look, don't look.
在 50 年代初 ， 我还想让拳击在美国所有城镇 ，
In the early '50s, I wanted to take boxing to every town in America,
但纽约市 wiseguys 不开心。
but the New York City wiseguys were not happy about that.
纽约市拳击是一项运动 ， 它仍然存在。
Boxing is a New York City sport, and that it's gonna remain.
但这是你的国家旅游电视抢足了风头的花园。
But this national television tour of yours is taking the spotlight off of the Garden.
并且 ， 我们买不起。
And that we can't afford.
嗯 ， 我。..
Well, I...
我想它能帮助你的。.. 弗兰克。
I think it'll help you in the long run... Frank.
如果你可以相信我的话。
If you can trust what I'm saying.
电视将成为全国性的消遣拳击
TV will turn boxing into a nationwide pastime
和你有才艺 ， 粉丝
and you'll have talent and fans
从全国各地来看锦标赛花园。
from every part of the country coming to see championships at the Garden.
我才不关心全国各地。
I don't give a shit about every part of the country.
纽约是母牛。
New York is the heart of the cow.
它的肉。 如果任何拳击迷 ， 想看一场比赛在前或在所述肉
It's the prime meat. If any boxing fan wants to see a fight in the flesh or in front
你肮脏的小管子 ， 更好的了解
of your little dirty tube, better understand
所有的道路都去到纽约。
that all roads go through New York.
当他们听到我幸存下来 ， 我们说好了。
When they heard I survived, we made a deal.
他们会饶我一命我一块钱也没有参赛。
They would spare my life as long as I never made another dollar from boxing.
这是一种熟悉的味道。
It's a familiar smell.
你在哪里 ？
Where were you?
什么 ， 你说什么呢 ？
What, what are you talking about?
你去那里 ？
Did you go there?
在哪里 ？
Where?
我就说嘛.. 哪里 ？
That's what I said... where?
请 ， 你让它听起来像我的女人或一些东西。
Please, you make it sound like I've been with some woman or something.
我宁愿你和别的女人。
I would rather you were with some woman.
不要总是成为一个地区检察官。
Don't always be a district attorney.
我见到一个老朋友。
I was seeing an old friend.
你知道 ， 它的罚款。
You know, it's fine.
我是金发。
I'm blonde.
我穿黑色。
I look great in black.
我将是一个非常热的寡妇。
I will be a very hot widow.
你想吗 ？ ”
Is that what you want?
多少年我还剩下什么 ？
How many years do I have left?
射线。
Ray.
这些人会杀了你。
These people will kill you.
嗯 ， 嗯。
Yeah, well.
我应该已经死了。
I might as well be dead already anyway.
哦 ， 多么可爱的事情要告诉你的妻子。
Oh, what a lovely thing to say to your wife.
"你喝醉了 ， 宝贝。 我的意思是。..
I don't mean... you, honey. I mean...
我们正在做什么。
we are what we do.
如果你只是赚钱 ， 成为你的钱。
And if you just make money, you become money.
这个东西每个人
This thing that everybody wants
人人都渴望 ， 这只是象征性的。
that everybody craves, it's just symbolic.
它没有真正的价值。
It has no real value.
我做一些我真正关心的事情。
I have to do something that I really care about.
我不是一个白痴。
I'm not an idiot.
我知道你很痛苦。
I know you're miserable.
我知道了 ， 但是这些动物统治一切。
I get it, but those animals run everything.
我宁愿生活在恐惧中。
I'd rather live in fear.
打起精神 ， 拿起来。
Pick it up a little, pick it up.
你得学会呼吸。
You're gonna have to learn to breathe.
和你要学习放慢步调。
And you're gonna learn to pace yourself.
有技术、有战略。
There's technique and there's strategy.
技术是你的一举一动 ， 你都
Technique is your every move, your every punch
覆盖你所有的短期决策。
covers all your short-term decisions.
战略是整个作战计划。
Strategy is your plan for the whole fight.
它的长期目标。
It's your long term.
它定义了如何应用该技术来实现你的主要目标。
It defines how you apply the technique to achieve your major goal.
如果你失败了一瞬
It's okay if your technique fails for a beat
只要你遵循这种策略。
as long as you're following the strategy.
布坎南知不知道你要他在第一回合被击败。
Buchanan knows you're gonna try to knock him out in the first round.
然后他就等你来 ， 试试
And then he'll wait for you to get tired and try
抓住你 ， 那是他的策略。
and catch you, and that's his strategy.
# comprende ？
#Comprende?
他期待。..
He expect...
但如果你慢下来
but if you slow down
去和。..
and go...
慢 ， 慢 ， 慢 ， 慢 ， 慢 ， 慢 ， 慢。..
slow, slow, slow, slow, slow, slow, slow...
布坎南没有 comprende 。
Buchanan no comprende.
束缚。
Get off the fence.
原谅我吗 ？
Excuse me?
束缚。
Get off the fence.
哦 ， 闭嘴 ， 笨蛋。
Ah, shut up, schmuck.
你以为你是谁 ， 老头 ？
Who do you think you are, old man?
我从哈莱姆线 arcel ， USA 。
I'm Ray Arcel from Harlem, USA.
你知道那是哪里 ？
You know where that is?
这将是未来世界冠军你说到这里。
And this is the future world champion you're talking to here.
他妈的关闭。
Fuck off.
他在狱中 ， 他认为他。
He's in a jail and he thinks he's in charge.
- 我们在监狱中。 - 不 ， 他 - 他在监狱中。
- We in jail. - No, he-he's in jail.
- 把他们监禁。 - 不 ， 不 ， 他..
- They put jail here. - No, no, he...
他。.. 这是所有的头。
He's... It's all in the head.
拳击是一项智力运动 ， 房水荧光素浓度。
Boxing is a mental sport, aquí.
控制你的身体是三分之一的工作。
What you do with your body is one-third of the job.
你要学着去当老板 ， 你是。
You got to learn to be the boss, which you are.
它说 ， “他在监狱里。”
Say it, "He's in jail."
说它。 “他在监狱里。”
Say it. "He's in jail."
- 他在监狱中。 - 他在监狱中。
- He's in jail. - He's in jail.
看到了吗 ？ 在监狱中。
See? In jail.
我想我告诉过你滚出去。
I thought I told you to fuck off.
你在监狱里。
You in jail.
你没完了 ， 是吧 ？
You don't know when to stop, do you?
你在监狱里。
You in jail.
- 好 ， 好。 - 你 ， 你在监狱里。
- Okay, okay. - You, you in jail.
得到了他妈的离开这里。
Get the fuck out of here.
- 你想要这个去 ？ - 你在监狱里。
- Is that the way you want this to go? - You in jail.
你是在监狱中。
You are in jail.
我是冠军。 这是巴拿马。
I'm champion. This is Panama.
好的。
Nice.
钩之后。 钩。
Hook after the right. Hook.
双。 刺拳。 刺拳。
Double up. Jab. Jab.
就这样就这样 ， 你去那里。
That's it, that's it, there you go.
你去那里。
There you go.
这就是它。 这就是它 ！
That's it. That's it!
不错 ， 不错。
Nice, nice.
Ciao 。
Ciao.
嘿 ， 你有了拳击手。
Hey, you are the boxer.
是的。
Yes.
你是谁 ？
And you are?
我听说你赢了。
I heard you won.
是的 ， 很方便。
Yeah, that was easy.
现在我的世界锦标赛。
Now I'm going for the world championship.
那很好。
That's good.
我可以陪你吗 ？
Can I walk with you?
你上过什么学校 ？
What school did you go to?
我去了 plomo qui? 学校。
I went to the Plomo Qui?ones school.
现在我在雷 arcel 。
Now I'm in the Ray Arcel.
射线 arcel ？
Ray Arcel?
嗯嗯。
Uh-huh.
美国学校呢 ？
American school?
是的 ， 美国的学校。
Yes, American school.
你没去学校 ， 你呢 ？
You didn't go to school, did you?
但你能阅读吗 ？
But you can read, right?
这像是工作面试。
This is like a job interview.
我以为你回家。
I thought I was walking you home.
是的。
Yes.
我可以继续。
I can continue alone.
为什么呢 ？
Why?
我们来自不同的世界。
We come from different worlds.
这是所有的头。
It's all in the head.
什么 ？
What?
这是所有的头。
It's all in the head.
把右手伸 ， 右手向内转动。
Turn the right hand over, turn the right hand over.
在未来的世界棋王首先需要被教导要幸运。
The first thing a future world champ needs to be taught is to be lucky.
幸运的是 ， 你必须学习如何勾引女人。
And luck is a woman you must learn to seduce.
是主角。
Be the host of the ring.
这就是你的殿宇 ， 人人如此。
This is your temple, and everyone does as you wish.
做时间的主人。
Be the master of time.
只有你和你要决定何时罢工。
You and only you should decide when to strike.
来看看。
Come see.
这里是厨房。
This is the kitchen.
用房水荧光素浓度。
Aquí.
我沉重的袋子。
My heavy bag.
一些香水。
Some perfumes.
来看看。
Come see.
我看着它。
I'm looking at it.
你不喜欢它吗 ？
You don't like it?
我只是习惯了。..
I'm just used to...
嘿 ， 雷。
Hey, Ray.
你怎么样 ， 嗯 ？
How you doing, huh?
别担心。
No worries.
你看起来很好。
You look good.
怎样的妻子 ？
How's the wife?
她很好 ， 谢谢。
She's good, thanks.
20 年的拳击英雄使命扩大到全国。
20 years since your heroic mission to expand boxing to the nation.
拳击膨胀。 我没有错。
Boxing expanded. I wasn't wrong.
YES 和 NO 。 但 ， 是的 ， 这使得运动的奇妙电视。
Yes and no. But yes, the sport makes for fantastic television.
现在你回来了。
And now you're back.
排序的。
Sort of.
我喜欢你 ， 雷。
I like you, Ray.
我真的为他们对你干了些什么。
I feel really bad for what they did to you.
我不需要买马的屁股 ， 知道还有东西在那里。
I don't need to look a gift horse up the ass to know there's shit in there.
我以为我们已有协定。
I thought we had a deal.
我们做的。
We do.
也许我很困惑什么我们正在谈论。
Maybe I'm confused about what kind of deal we're talking about.
你不应该把钱从拳击。
You weren't meant to make money from boxing again.
我训练他的自由。
I'm training him for free.
您可以检查与卡洛斯 eleta 。
You can check with Carlos Eleta.
他的经理。
He's the fighter's manager.
你是个漂亮的家伙 ， 但你不会教我怎么藏钱。
You're a classy guy, but you're not going to teach me how to hide money.
布坎南的 14 对三个 Dur á n ， 对吧 ？
Buchanan's favored 14 to three against Durán, right?
是的。
That's right.
除了 Dur á n 能获胜。
Except Durán's going to win.
把钱全花在 Dur á n 。
Put all your money on Durán.
大赚一笔。
Make a bundle.
别管我获胜 ， 如果我失去他。
Leave me alone if he wins, shoot me if he loses.
你是个高贵人
You're a classy guy.
Mr. arcel ， 为什么从退休的没有 ？
Mr. Arcel, why come back from retirement with an unproven fighter?
我才刚满 73 。
I just turned 73.
你知道 ， 七十年而变化。
You know, seven decades and change.
布朗和我和弗雷迪已经忘记这里也许更多
And myself and Freddy Brown here have probably forgotten more
比大多数导师学习。
than most trainers will ever learn.
但我清楚地记得 ， 从 20 年代到 50 年代
But I remember well, from the '20s to the '50s
我们生活在黄金时代的拳击。
we lived the golden age of boxing.
然后电视接手
Then television took over
和我们大家都变了.. 雄心勃勃。
and we all became... ambitious.
这项运动变成了一个奇观 ， 演出。
The sport turned into a spectacle, show business with blood.
并且做的好, 因为我们到达观众没人想到我们会达成。
And it was a good thing, because we reached audiences nobody thought we could reach.
这个问题无疑是对战士开始做的时候
The problem, inevitably, is that the fighters started doing it
对于名声、贪婪、以自我为中心。
for the fame, for greed, for self-importance.
独立启动子的消失,
Independent promoters faded away and, with them,
真正的战士饿了 ， 这个游戏的生命线。
the true hungry fighters, the lifeblood of this game.
但是 ， 今天晚上你就会遇见最好的轻量化
Tonight, however, you'll meet the best lightweight
在纽约有 50 年。
New York has seen in 50 years.
一个真正的、真正的饥饿。
A true, true hungry fighter.
像在过去一样。
Like in the old days.
他的灵魂、精神能量和确定的运动 ，
He's got the soul, the rage, the mental energy and determination the sport needs,
这就是为什么我在这里。
and that's why I'm here.
因为拳击的一个新的黄金时代始于 Roberto Dur á n 。
Because a new golden era for boxing begins with Roberto Durán.
以 28 胜、零损失、 24 脱模。..
With 28 wins, zero losses and 24 knockouts...
来自贫民区的 EL chorrillo Panama 。..
from the slums of El Chorrillo, Panama...
..roberto. Dur á n 。
...Roberto Durán.
轻量级世界冠军 ， Ken Buchanan 。
The lightweight champion of the world, Ken Buchanan.
他的裙子吗 ？
He's got a skirt?
他穿着一条裙子 ， Roberto ！
He is wearing a skirt, Roberto!
该死的裙子 ！
A fuckin' skirt!
带他去看电影。
Take him to the movies.
他的魅力。 让他敞开心扉。
Charm him. Let him open up.
然后他去上班。
Then go to work on him.
记得我们。 战略。
Remember what we worked on. Strategy.
对不起。
Excuse me.
他们在打斗吗 ？
Are they fighting yet?
它开始。
It's about to start.
Dur á n 当然是试图提高他的九个回合淘汰赛。
Durán is certainly trying to improve on his nine one-round knockouts here.
他倾其所有。
He's throwing everything.
约翰尼 ， 分数为击倒。
Johnny scores it as a knockdown.
找到尸体 ！
Find that body!
投诉人是有点过度紧张。
The challenger is a little over-anxious.
它几乎是布坎南所击倒。
It was almost Buchanan scoring the knockdown.
杀死他 ， 好了 ！
Kill him, cholo!
Dur á n 可以冲了出来。
Durán may punch himself out.
不要在匆忙。 你找到他。 他只是不断。
Don't rush in. You got him. Just keep on him.
记住该策略。 他要你感到厌烦。
Remember the strategy. He wants you to get tired.
我不关心这个战略。
I don't care about the strategy.
- 我要杀了他。 - 听我说。
- I'll kill him. - Listen to me.
如果你不在的佯攻和猛击 ，
If you don't go in with a feint and a jab,
他要你在指甲上的方式。 他个子高。
he's going to nail you on the way in. He's tall.
他来说太高了。
He's-he's too tall for you.
战略。 坚持的策略。
Strategy. Stick with the strategy.
- 滚开。 - 不 ， 不要告诉我。
- Fuck off. - No, don't tell me that.
不要对我说那些事情。
Don't say those things to me.
他妈的关闭。 是啊 ， 是啊 ， 他高高的个子, 帮我。
Fuck off. Yeah, yeah, he's tall and he's gonna nail me.
什么 ， 你为他工作?
What, you work for him or what?
- 你疯了吗 ？ - 是啊 ， 他比我高。..
- Are you out of your mind? - Yeah, he's taller than me...
我在这里做什么 ？ 我不需要这个。
What am I doing here? I don't need this.
是啊 ， 因为他的外国佬。
Yeah, because he's gringo.
- 听着 ， 你这个小讨厌鬼。 - 对吗 ？
- Listen, you stupid little schmuck. - Right?
你想让我离开这里 ？
You want me to leave here?
我可以把你自己的角落里。
I can leave you in the corner by yourself.
现在 ， 举止文明 ， 行为像大人一样 ，
Now behave yourself, act like a grown-up,
- 别孩子气。 - 我他妈的跟你。
- and stop being a baby. - I'm fucking with you.
- 我很紧张 ， 好吗 ？ - 我知道你是谁 ， 我知道你很紧张
- I'm nervous, okay? - I know you are, I know you're nervous,
- 但是你看他。 - 别让我太糟了 ， 好吗 ？
- but look at him. - Don't make me worse, okay?
我的.. 你使自己更糟糕。
I'm... You're making yourself worse.
- 好吧 ， 放松一下吧。 - 你的 … … 不 ， 你放松。
- Okay, relax now. - You're mak... no, you relax.
你走出去 ， 你告诉我你能做什么。
You get out there and you show me what you can do.
你要一步一步来。
You pace yourself.
你是老板。
You be the boss.
保持压力 ， 要求他在背后伤人。
Keep the pressure on him behind the jabs.
开始工作的主体。
Start working on the body.
维持压力。这就是一学就会 ， 一学就会保持他的压力。
Keep the pressure on... that's... keep the pressure on him.
怎么了?
What's going on?
Dur á n 和那的敲除。
Durán's going for that knockout.
这是一个白人婊子 ， 好了 ！
That's a white bitch, Cholo!
ESO una perra 布兰卡 ， 好了 ！
Eso una perra blanca, Cholo!
哦 ！
Oh!
他很疼他。
He really hurt him that time.
布坎南有麻烦了 ，..
Buchanan's in trouble...
他让他的狗屎 ！
Make him shit his pants!
布坎南说出去 ！
Buchanan's mouthpiece goes out!
记住 ， 布坎南来自一个破碎的家庭。
Remember, Buchanan came from a broken home.
把他逼到绳子 ！
Get him up against the ropes!
好了 ！
Cholo!
约翰尼。 约翰尼。
Johnny. Johnny.
这是个干净。
That was a clean shot.
你得知道。
You gotta know that.
我们在纽约 ， 不要忘记 ， 不要忘记。
We're in New York City, don't forget, don't forget.
- 我没打他的球。 - 不 ， 不。
- I didn't hit him in the, in the balls. - No, no.
- 我击中他的要害。 - 不 ， 相信我 ， 我知道。
- I hit him in the gut. - No, believe me, I know.
Dur á n! Dur á n!
Durán! Durán!
他好了。
He's good.
- 他很好。 - 我可以听到你。
- He's good. - I can hear you.
我可以听到你的声音 ， 我很好。
I can hear you, I'm okay.
- 我很好。 - 他很好。
- I'm okay. - He's good.
嘿 ！
Hey!
Dur á n, Dur á n, Dur á n, Dur á n, Dur á n!
Durán, Durán, Durán, Durán, Durán!
嘿 ！
Hey!
我们爱你 ， 巴拿马 ！
We love you, Panama!
Dur á n, Dur á n, Dur á n...
Durán, Durán, Durán...
哦 ， 哦 ， 哦 ， 哦 ， 哦 ， 哦。..
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh-oh...
嘿 ， 雷 ！ 干杯。
Hey, Ray! Cheers.
- 我有个问题问你。 - 是啊。
- I got a question for you. - Yeah.
为什么你总是撩拨着我的头发 ？
Why you always brushed my hair when we were in the corners?
拳击手猛击你 ， 感觉骄傲。
Fighter punches you, feels proud.
钟的声音 ， 开始下一轮 ， 你出来找新鲜 ，
Bell sounds, next round starts, you come out looking all fresh,
像刚洗完澡。
like you just came out of the shower.
驱使他疯了。 他认为他不能伤害你。
Drives him nuts. He thinks he can't hurt you.
所有心理。
All psychological.
哦。..
Oh...
- 策略。 - 策略。
- Strategy. - Strategy.
- 啊哈。 - 策略。
- Aha. - Strategy.
啊哈 ， 你笨蛋。
Aha, you schmuck.
- 嗯 ？ - 现在你说话。
- Huh? - Now you're speaking Yiddish.
- 是啊。 - 是的。
- Yeah. - Yes.
“schmlendeck 。”
"Schmlendeck."
schmendrick 。 三上三下。
Schmendrick. Putz.
是啊 ， 儿子。
Yeah, son of a putz.
- 嘿 ， 小心我的头发凝胶。 - 不 ， 不 ， 我只是 … …
- Hey, watch my hair gel. - No, no, I just...
我只是 … …
I just...
是啊。
Yeah.
打开我的肚子 ！
Open my belly!
别打开她的肚子 ！
Don't open her belly!
empuja 。
Empuja.
我们怎么叫他 ？
How do we call him?
Roberto Duran 。
Roberto Duran.
是个女孩 ！
It's a girl!
另一个女孩
Another girl
Roberto Dur á n 。
Roberto Durán.
你不能把他们的名字全都罗伯托。
You can't name them all Roberto.
让他的名字 ， 那么 ， 就像罗宾汉。
Let's name him Robin, then, like Robin Hood.
我们打击富人给穷人。
We fight the rich to give the poor.
另一个男孩和他的名字是罗伯特 ・ Dur á n 。
Another boy and his name is Roberto Durán.
而且我不想听到它。
And I don't wanna hear it.
怎样的女孩 ？ 你吃过吗 ？
How are the girls? Did you eat?
是的 ！
Yes!
买一些苏打水。
Get some sodas.
怎么了 ？
What's wrong?
帕皮 ， 我们已经送出 100 大。
Papi, we've given away 100 grand already.
有什么问题吗 ？
What's the problem?
我们拿到钱。 和它的好。
We got money. And it's good to give.
看起来每个人都是多么幸福。
Look how happy everyone is.
谢谢你的食物 ， Dur á n 。
Thanks for the food, Durán.
跳 ！ 跳 ！
Jump! Jump!
我们是来参加
We are here to participate in
该条约的签署 ， 将保证和平与繁荣。..
the signing of treaties which will assure a peaceful and prosperous...
..of 。美国认为公平
...of the United States to the belief that fairness
并不强制
and not force
应该是我们的世界各国。
should lie at the heart of our dealings with the nations of the world.
尊敬的卡特总统。
Dear Mr. President Carter.
以真理的逻辑 ， 我想说 ，
In the name of the truth of logic, I would like to say,
我们将签署这个条约。
that we will sign this treaty.
他签署的条约 ！
He's signing the treaty!
该条约签订 ！ 该运河是我们的了 ！
The treaty is signed! The Canal is ours!
金发女郎 ！
Blondie!
他们会给我们的渠道 ！
They're gonna give us the canal!
托里霍斯将军签署的条约 ！
General Torrijos signed the treaty!
相信看到这个单词 Yankee 。
See to believe the word of a Yankee.
来看看我得到了你。
Come see what I got you.
但等待.. 这是很重要的。
But wait... this is important.
托里霍斯是良好的。 - 你想看到真正的巴拿马运河 ？
- Torrijos is good with the people. - You wanna see the real Panama canal?
我看到小运河。
I've seen that tiny canal a million times.
你说因为你是一个帆船。
You say that because all you have is a sail boat.
帆的船吗 ？ 我在这里得到了泰坦尼克号。
A sail boat? I got the Titanic here.
然后 ， 宿。
Sink it then.
巴拿马庆祝都是露宿街头 ， 甚至你不快乐吗 ？
All Panama is celebrating in the streets and you are not even happy?
幸福是什么 ？
Happy about what?
关于什么 ？
About what?
显然你们从未被追逐的船舶。
You've obviously never been chased by a Marine.
原谅我吗 ？
Excuse me?
富家小姐。
Rich girl.
离我远点。
Get off of me.
现在你会生气吗 ？
Now you gonna get mad?
是的。 你在胡说什么。
Yes. You're talking shit.
嗯 ？
Eh?
他们回到自己的领地。
They offer to return your own territory in 1999.
在 20 年 ！
In twenty years!
他妈的的缘故 ， 它是我们的了 ！
For fuck's sake, it's ours!
和它做穷人还是富人。
And it has nothing to do with being rich or poor.
这是个常识。
It's common sense.
现在不行。 3 “我和你生气的样子。
Now this is fucked. I'm celebrating and you are pissed.
如果你想让你骄傲的人 ，
If you wanna make your people proud,
这是最难以击败的车手。
this is the guy to beat.
它说什么 ？
What does it say?
你什么时候能学会阅读吗 ？
When are you gonna learn to read?
它说什么 ？
What does it say?
说它 “战斗机” 。
It says "Fighter of the year".
年度 ？ 这个小丑 ？
Fighter of the year? This clown?
他没有打过仗 ， 在人的生命。
He hasn't fought a man in his life.
他是美国体育的象征。
He is the symbol of American sports.
我的球。
My balls.
他是美国体育的象征。
He's the symbol of American Sports.
如果你想要你的托里霍斯 － 卡特条约。..
If you want your Torrijos-Carter treaty...
对于这个国家意味着什么。..
to mean anything for this country...
1999 年以前。。。
before 1999...
摧毁他们的偶像 ， 让他们尊重巴拿马。
destroy their idol and make them respect Panama.
偶像 ， 是一个圆形。
That idol goes down in one round.
让我看看。
Let me see it.
我对你有 15 次以上。
For you I got 15 rounds or more.
哇。
Wow.
他像闪电一样快 ， 这家伙。
He's lightning fast, this guy.
他模仿阿里。
He's imitating Ali.
出拳像女孩。
Punches like a girl.
是啊 ， 但是别人能从你一整晚
Yeah, but he could run away from you all night
和许多的得分点与这些冲头。
and score dozens of points with these punches.
他跳。 看看他。
He's jumping all over the place. Look at him.
我的意思是 ， 像 ， 呃 ， 他是一个不同种类的动物。
I mean, it's like, uh, he's a different kind of animal.
你得对你的工作速度。
You gotta work on your speed.
男人 ， 如果你这么爱他 ， 你为什么不去训练 ？
Man, if you love him so much, why don't you go train him?
我不喜欢他 ， 我尊重他。
I don't love him, I respect him.
和你要心疼一下自己 ， 并且尊重他。
And you should do yourself a favor and respect him, too.
- 看看他。 - 不, 只要去雷 ，
- Look at him. - No, but go, Ray,
去按摩肩膀和你爱的那么多。
go and massage the shoulders you love so much.
- 哦 ， 拜托 ， 住手 ， 不来。 - 嗯 ？ 我现在这么慢 ？
- Oh, come on, stop it, come on. - Huh? So now am I slow?
- 我不知道 ， 停止。 - 现在我慢 ？
- I don't know, whatever, stop it. - Now am I slow?
- 不 ， 去他的肩膀按摩。 - 我。你.. 。..
- No, go and massage his shoulders. - I... you're...
- 去你的外国佬。 - 哦。..
- Go with your gringo, Ray. - Oh...
也许你已经训练了他。
Maybe you've been training him already.
我不知道你去哪里。
I don't know where you go at night.
你 ， 你在和我开玩笑。 Roberto ！
You, you've gotta be kidding me. Roberto!
- 嗯 ？ 没有吗 ？ - 来吧 ， 停止它。 闭嘴。 长大。
- Huh? No? - Come on, stop it. Shut up. Grow up.
不是所有的一切都围绕着你。
Not everything revolves around you.
我有责任。 来吧 ， 看看这个..
I have responsibilities. Come on, look at this...
他们必须知道也有这个 ， 我不可能去拍。..
They must know that-that-that I won't be able to beat...
- - 打他。
to-to-to-to beat him.
这个就交给我了 ， 你知道吗 ？
I will beat him, you know?
我就打死他 ， 因为我是个好拳手。
I will beat him because I'm a good boxer.
- 你知道吗 ？ - 哦 ！ 现在 ， 坐下。
- And you know what? - Strategize right now and sit down.
我将使他在战斗。
I will make him fight like a man.
- 所以我们可以坐下来讨论事情。 - 我找过了。
- Sit down so we can discuss everything. - I'm done looking.
没有去。
No go.
我就打死他。 我的计策。
I will beat him. With my strategy.
如果你离开 ， 我打包行李中。 我走了。
If you leave, I'm packing my bags. I'm going.
- 离开。 - 你离开了 ， 我会离开。
- Leave. - You leave, I'll leave.
- 是我的客人。 - 啊。..
- Be my guest. - Ah...
他妈的 schmendrick 。
Goddamn schmendrick.
你他妈的 ， 他妈的 schmendrick 。
Goddamn you, fucking schmendrick.
去告诉你父亲 ， 我的根 ， 好吗 ？
And you tell your father, root for me, okay?
太可爱了。
Too cute.
那不是 Dur á n ？
Isn't that Durán?
呃. 嗯.. 。
Uh... yeah.
你知道他在这里吗 ？
You know he was here?
Manos de Piedra ！
Manos de Piedra!
看看有钱人的孩子。
Look at the rich kid.
他是一名真正的战士 ？
He's a real fighter?
- 还是小丑 ？ - 嘿。
- Or a clown? - Hey.
尊重、 Dur á n 。 他与他的妻子。
Respect, Durán. He's with his wife.
什么 ， 这个婊子养的 ？
What, this son of a bitch here?
- 或者是你说的是妓女 ？ - 嘿 ， 嘿。
- Or are you talking about the whore? - Hey, hey.
嘿 ， 嘿 ， 你放尊重点 ， 兄弟。
Hey, hey, you show some respect, man.
- 你跟我说 ， 你一块狗屎 ？
You talking to me, you piece of shit?
你知道你是什么 ？
You know what you are?
男人味 ， 采取狗屎离开这里。
Take that machismo bullshit out of here.
我看见的金勺子儿童
All I see is a golden spoon child
他认为 ， 打仗的人。 打仗的男人吗 ？
who thinks he can fight a man. You can fight a man?
- 嘿 ， 闭嘴。 - 你打仗的男人吗 ？
- Hey, shut up. - You can fight a man?
让我们离开这里 ， 雷。
Let's get out of here, Ray.
- 来吧。 - 你是猫 ， 男人。
- Come on. - You're a pussy, man.
你是一个小丑。 所有你做的就是跳舞和跳跃。
You're a clown. All you do is dance and jump around.
和卖汽水而上涨。
Jump around and sell soda.
他抽你的屁股。
He's gonna whip your ass.
- 你闭嘴 ， 婊子。 - 哦 ， 你他妈的 ！
- You shut up, too, bitch. - Oh, fuck you!
我要操你丈夫, 当我办完了 ， 我去
I'm gonna fuck your husband in the ring and when I'm done with him, I'm gonna go
- 和你 ， 宝贝。 - 哦 ， 你一学就会 ！
- and fuck you all night, baby. - Oh, you...!
他们想干么 ？
Gonna fuck them here, huh?
你怎么了 ？
What is wrong with you?
你洗你的嘴之前你跟一个女人 ！
You wash your mouth before you talk to a woman!
现在 ， 现在 ， 混蛋。
Right now, right now, motherfucker.
我大老远跑来 ， 从巴拿马到战斗的人。
I come all the way, all the way from Panama to fight a man.
所有和他们给我的是一个漂亮的男孩。 他妈的是什么 ？
And all they give me is a pretty boy. What the fuck?
你看 ， 你看他 ， 他的健怡可乐广告 ？
And you see, and you see his, um, his diet cola commercial?
他自称 “糖”
And he calls himself "Sugar"
他和你妈不含糖。
and he's selling you sugar-free shit.
或者 ， 或许 ， 或许 ， 我们有。
Or-or maybe, maybe that's what we're gonna have.
不含食糖的战斗。
A sugar-free fight.
啊 ， 啊 ， 啊 ， 啊 ， 啊 ， 啊 ！
Ah-ah, ah-ah, ah-ah!
我很抱歉 ， 好吗 ？
I'm sorry, okay?
对不起不够好。
Sorry's not good enough.
你怎么可以这样 ？ 侮辱一个女人吗 ？
How could you do that? Insult a woman like that?
你怎么了 ？
What's the matter with you?
嗯 ， 我的国家羞辱你。
Well, my country felt insulted by yours.
并不是只有女性。
And not only women.
儿童。
Children.
你有跟你说话的方式到那个女人 ？
What does your country have to do with the way you talked to that woman?
的方式来表现 ？
The way you behaved?
你知道的.. 你知道的 ， 饿吗 ？
You know how... you know how it is to be hungry?
别和我说 ， “饥饿” 。
And I don't say, "hungry" hungry.
饿了 ， 你必须去。..
To be hungry that you have to go to...
- 垃圾食品 ？
to-to the garbage for food?
虽然美国军队正在开发 ？
While the American army is exploiting your country?
你知道那种感觉吗 ？
You know how it feels?
你说什么 ？ 刚才你怎么回事 ？
What does that have to do with what you just did?
你。.. 你在做什么 ？
What are you... what are you doing?
- 嗯 ， 它已经做。.. - 你知道 ， 你想 ，
- Well, it has to do... - You know, you want to be,
你想 ， 你想成为一名战士 ，
you want to be, you want to be a warrior,
你想报仇的人 ， 我听着。
you want to avenge your people, fine by me.
你的报仇人。 要成为一位战士。
Avenge your people. Be a warrior.
但真正的勇士 ， 不要做你所做。
But real warriors do not do what you did.
他们不是好惹的 ， 你刚才做的。
They don't mess with women the way you just did.
如果你想让我和你说话 ， 你不能再这么做。
And if you want me in your corner, you cannot do that again.
好 ， 好 ， 好 ， 好 ， 对不起 ， 对不起。
Well, well, okay, okay, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
但我不会说我向他道歉。
But I'm not gonna say I'm sorry to him.
我说我对不起你 ， 但我不会说我向他道歉。
I say I'm sorry to you, but I'm not gonna say I'm sorry to him.
让我们忘掉它。
Let's forget it.
What 's done is done.
What's done is done.
你疯了吗 ？
Are you mad?
而且。..
And let's just...
专注备战。
focus on the fight.
你感到愤怒 ， 我理解这一点。
This anger you feel, I understand that.
你不想害你自己心目中的游戏。
You don't want to become a victim of your own mind game.
这是所有的头。
It's all in the head.
罗伯特。
Robert.
你为什么在这里 ？
Why are you here?
嗯 ？
Huh?
如果发现你的死亡射线。
If Ray finds out you are dead.
我无法入睡。
I can't sleep.
怎么了 ？
What's wrong?
我也不想让他们失望。
I don't want to disappoint tomorrow.
爸爸 ！
Dad!
嘿 ！
Hey!
“我的孩子 ！ 早上好 ！
My babies! Good morning!
替爸爸亲吻。
Kisses for Daddy.
等不及看到你杀死一个懦夫 ！
Can't wait to see you kill that coward!
别这么说 ！
Don't say that!
但爸爸说它在电视上。
But Dad said it on TV.
这是我说的那些事情。
It's my job to say those things.
所以你不能杀他吗 ？
So you're not gonna kill him?
当然 ， 我要杀了那个狗娘养的。
Of course, I'm gonna kill that son of a bitch.
它所有的节目。 他说 ， 这样的战斗更加有趣。
It's all a show. He says that so the fight is more fun.
去穿衣服。
Come get dressed.
Dur á n 已成为观众最喜爱的
Durán has turned into the audience favorite
之后的训练过程。
after a menacing training process in town.
他那样咄咄逼人。
He has been so aggressive.
今晚的裁判是 Carlos Padilla ， 见证辉煌
The referee tonight is Carlos Padilla, who gloriously oversaw
在马尼拉的拳王之战弗雷泽和阿里之间。
the Thrilla in Manila between Frazier and Ali.
你必须告诉他们 ， 否则你会看到的
You have to let them fight, otherwise you're gonna see
两个家伙跑了整整一夜。
two guys running all night.
去你的角落。 去你的角落。
To your corner. To your corner.
我看到的最大的环。
Biggest ring I ever saw.
Sugar Ray Leonard!
- 人们在嘲笑冠军是。.. - 嘘 ？
- The crowd is booing the champ... - Booing?
..in 。必须什么令人吃惊之处 ；
...in what must be startling for Leonard,
在如今这个体育场非常惊讶这个星球赢得奥运金牌。
who, in this very stadium surprised the planet by winning Olympic gold.
《美好的一天。
It's a wonderful day.
好吧 ， 宝贝 ！
That's okay, baby!
这是你的夜晚今晚 ！
It's your night tonight!
你死定了 ， Dur á n!
You're dead meat, Durán!
- 是的。 - 你什么都不是。
- That's right. - You're nothing.
他妈的好了 ！
Fuckin' Cholo!
是啊。
Yeah.
让他靠近你的身体。 不追逐女人。
Keep him close to your body. Don't chase the lady.
让她来找你。 别让她跑了。
Let her come to you. Don't let her run.
而失去的比运行。
Rather lose than run.
看看他。
Look at him.
。。。 15 个回合的拳击赛。..
...15 rounds of boxing...
战略。
Strategy.
由启动子。..
Presented by the promoter...
这个加拿大潘咳巳河祷 Roberto Dur á n 。
This Canadian crowd has embraced the underdog Roberto Durán.
投机行为猖獗
Speculation has been rampant
伦纳德是否将这种街头打架
over whether Leonard will turn this into a street fight
还是回到了拳 ， 把他带到这儿来的。
or go back to the boxing which brought him here.
Leonard 和 Dur á n!
Leonard and Durán!
Dur á n 才与伦纳德的出拳。
Durán getting inside the jab of Leonard.
看着他 ！ 留着他的绳子 ！ 看着他 ！
At him! Keep him on the ropes! At him!
两个拳击手在比赛中发挥出色。
Two fighters at the top of their game.
刺拳! 刺拳! 刺拳!
Jab! Jab! Jab!
停留在他身上 ！ 停留在他身上 ！
Stay on him! Stay on him!
快出来 ， 快出来 ！
Get out of there, get out of there!
- 别打架了。 - 那不是伦纳德。
- Break it up. - That's not Leonard.
伦纳德的拳短 ， 而不是广泛的。
Leonard is short punches, not wide ones.
它打破了。
Break it up.
平时难以捉摸的 Leonard 住措手不及。
The normally elusive Leonard is staying flat-footed.
他想跟 Dur á n 和退缩。
He wants to trade with Durán and not back down.
他想证明他是个男人。
He wants to prove he's a man.
让他觉得他的抵抗。
Let him feel he's resisting.
希望留住他直到他的灵感 ， 然后杀了他。
Keep him hoping until he's inspired and then kill him.
看着我 ！
Look at me!
你他妈的是谁 ？ 嗯 ？
Who the fuck are you today? Huh?
这是我的荣誉而战。
This is honor I'm fighting for.
操你妈 ！
Fuck that shit!
让他战斗。
Make him fight.
去找他 ， 冠军 ！
Go get him, champ!
他跑了 ！
Run him around!
Dur á n! Dur á n! Dur á n!
Durán! Durán! Durán!
Dur á n! Dur á n!
Durán! Durán!
Dur á n 一记左钩拳将摆动脖子 ， 伦纳德 ！
Durán lands a left hook to the neck that wobbles Leonard!
脚踝 ！ 脚踝 ！
Ankles! Ankles!
Dale 出岔 Tu Madre!
Dale Chucha tu Madre!
这是不对 Leonard 我们看到。
This is not the Leonard we're used to seeing.
你能相信他试着用男子气概吗 ？
Can you believe he's trying to match macho with macho?
Dur á n 推回。
Durán pushes back.
Leonard 有一些餐厅。
Leonard has some room now.
好吧 Leonard 手。
Good right hand by Leonard.
打破。 打开。 打开。
Break. Open. Open.
关键是 Leonard 他的左刺拳。
The key to Leonard is his left jab.
但这也是挡在你的腿。
But it's also working in tandem with those legs.
现在 ， 他好像措手不及 ， 只是想在 Dur á n 。
Right now, seems like he's flat-footed, just trying to tee off on Durán.
去 ！ 打败他!
Go! Beat him!
现在 ， 雷的战斗的战斗。
Now, Sugar Ray is fighting an inspired fight.
你要他离开 ， 丘洛。
You gotta try to knock him out, Cholo.
你永远不知道这些该死的法官。
You never know with these darn judges.
他们可以采取行动。
They can take the fight away from us.
这是您表现最好的战斗。
This has been your best fight.
但你仍然是人类。
But you're still human.
你仍然可能会输掉。
You could still lose.
我想请你注意。
I want you to focus.
我们要的是冠军吗 ？
Are we gonna be champions?
Tu Eres Mi ó n Campe Hydroservice 有限公司所有 ， 未经书面允许。
Tu eres mi campeón.
被绳索。
Against the ropes.
最后一轮 ， 冠军 ！
Last round, champ!
现在或者永不 ！
Now or never!
15 回合 ！
Round 15!
不是很多人都以为他们会这样做。
Not many thought it would come to this.
观众全都站了起来。
The crowd is on their feet.
并且在这里在蒙特利尔。
And at the battle here in Montreal.
- 我们是在最后时刻的战斗。 - 走 ， 走 ！
- We are in the waning moments of this fight. - Go, go!
我不能相信我看到的。
I cannot believe what I'm seeing.
我不能相信正在发生什么的。
I cannot believe what is taking place.
到了最后 ， 这两个战士扑向他们。
To the very end, these two warriors going at it.
就像他们知道的钟声就要响。
Like they don't know that a bell is going to ring.
这就是我们的职责所在。
This is what we are here for.
我们正在见证历史。
We are witnessing history.
丘洛 ， 打晕他 ！
Cholo, knock him out!
谁想要更多 ？
Who wants it more?
走吧 ， 好了 ！
Let's go, Cholo!
惊人的战斗 ！
An amazing battle!
我们在 15 回合。
And we're in the 15th round.
这是要去战斗 ！
This fight is gonna go all the way!
我们正在倒计时。
We are counting down.
六 ， 四 ， 三 … …
Six, five, four, three...
和铃就要响 ！
And the bell is going to ring!
他们来了 ！
Here they are!
看看这两位战士 ！
Look at these two warriors!
行为 ， 举止 ， 行为 ！
Behave, behave, behave!
- 我们会得到惩罚 ， 表现。 - 你他妈的 ！
- We could get penalized, behave. - You shit!
我们之前也见过 ， 在战斗中被关闭。
We've seen this before, when a fight is close.
通常将决定冠军队伍。
The decision usually goes to the champion.
现在谁是婊子 ？ 现在谁是婊子 ， 狗娘养的 ？
Who's the cunt now? Who's the cunt now, motherfucker?
- Maric ó n! - 操你 ！
- Maricón! - Fuck you!
你是我的婊子 ！
You are my bitch!
罗比 ！
Robbie!
你赢了 ， 我的爱 ！
You won, my love!
三位评委的分数如下 ：
Three judges score the fight as follows:
法官 poletti Angelo
Judge Angelo Poletti
调用匹配 147 ～ 147 。
calls the match 147 to 147.
它是一场平局。
It is a draw.
冷静 ， 我的爱。
Be calm, my love.
Judge Harry Gibbs 调用匹配
Judge Harry Gibbs calls the match
144 - 145 。 - 你证明了自己。
- 145 to 144. - You've proven yourself.
罗伯托的 Dur á n 。
for Roberto Durán.
关注。 关注。
Attention. Attention.
法官 baldeyrou
Judge Raymond Baldeyrou
调用匹配 144 至 146 。
calls the match 146 to 144.
- 新的中量级。.. - 是啊 ！
- The new welterweight... - Yeah!
..champion 。世界 ， Roberto Dur á n!
...champion of the world, Roberto Durán!
你好。
Hello.
我在从康尼岛医院
I'm calling from the Coney Island Hospital
对于患者而言为过量吸食海洛因。
in regards to a patient with a heroin overdose.
- 是吗 ？ - 病人
- Yes? - Patient's records
指示她的女儿雷 arcel 。
indicate she's the daughter of Ray Arcel.
不 ， TH - 这是雷的妻子 arcel ，
No, th-this is the wife of Ray Arcel,
我和丈夫有一个女儿。
and my husband does not have a daughter.
你一定是打错号码了。
You must have the wrong number.
- 对不起 ， 女士。 - 不 ， 不用担心。 晚上好。
- Sorry, ma'am. - Nope, no worries. Good night.
什么事 ？
What happened?
没有什么。 有人拨错了号码。
Nothing. It was just a wrong number.
他们怎么说 ？
What'd they say?
他们说还有另一个名叫雷 arcel
They said there's another guy named Ray Arcel
和他的女儿是在医院。
and his daughter is in the hospital.
什么医院 ？ - 什么事 ？
What hospital? What-what happened?
我不知道 ， 但我知道我不可能回去睡觉了。
I don't know, but I know I'm not gonna be able to go back to sleep now.
你在干什么 ？
What are you doing?
噢 ， 耶稣。
Aw, Jesus.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
我理解你的病人。
I understand you're related to the patient.
是的 ， 我父亲和她 ， 嗯 ，
Yes, I'm her father and, uh,
我 ， 呃 ， 是的。..
I'll, uh, be responsible for anything that...
你为什么在这里 ？
Why are you here?
这些年你喝醉了吗 ？
All these years... you come now?
为什么呢 ？
Why?
你没有培养战斗机吗 ？
You have no fighters to-to nurture?
你在这里干什么 ？
What are you doing here?
我不想这样出去。
I don't want to be seen like this.
我不是你的战士。
I'm not one of your fighters.
黑泽尔和我不能有孩子。
Hazel and I couldn't have kids.
和我们的.. 想收养。
And we... wanted to adopt.
当我们采用和阿黛尔 Adele, 四个成员 ， 去世了。
We adopted Adele and when Adele was four, Hazel passed away.
我不知道要做什么。 我没有钱。
I didn't know what to do. I had no money.
我可以照顾她。 我的..
I couldn't take care of her. I...
我以为她最好。 我的..
I-I thought she'd be better off with my in-laws. I...
我 ， 嗯。..
I was, uh...
- 我知道我应该告诉你 ， 我是。.. - 告诉我吗 ？
- I know I should have told you, I was... - Told me?
她做了什么?
What about her?
这个女孩挂在她的生命在医院的病床上吗 ？
What about the girl hanging on to her life by a thread in a hospital bed?
当然。 伦纳德。
Sure. Leonard.
你现在是我的朋友。
You are my friend now.
宝贝 ， 我要去。.. 我想给你看样东西。
Baby, I want to show... I want to show you something.
是吗 ？
Yeah?
你想告诉我吗 ？
What do you want to show me?
- 嗯.. - 要进去吗 ？
- Uh... - Want to go in there?
是的我们会的
Yeah, we will.
但我 - 我想给你看样东西之前我们做的 ， 好吗 ？
But I-I want to show you something before we do, okay?
只。只是让我一学就会。..
Just... just let me...
让我去。..
let me...
尊重 ..have. Sugar Ray Leonard?
...have respect for Sugar Ray Leonard?
当然。
Sure.
当然。 伦纳德。
Sure. Leonard.
你现在是我的朋友。
You are my friend now.
看看这个。
Look at this.
伦纳德。
Leonard.
你现在是我的朋友。
You are my friend now.
一直以来 ， 他故意这么做的。
All along, he's been doing this on purpose.
他伤害你把我逼疯了。
He hurt you to drive me crazy.
让我来
To get me to be
在他的硬汉气概。
in his macho tough guy war.
雷 ， 你很困惑。
Ray, you're obsessed.
我告诉你 ， 这是一个策略。
I'm telling you, it's a strategy.
它是一个战略。..
It's been a strategy...
我要操你丈夫的戒指
I'm gonna fuck your husband in the ring
当我办完了 ， 我和你 ， 宝贝。
and when I'm done with him, I'm gonna go and fuck you all night, baby.
他侮辱了你 ， 他知道他可以得到我的头
From the moment he insulted you, he knew that he could get in my head
使我去与他。
and cause me to stand toe-to-toe with him.
我从来没丢。
I've never lost.
我不会输。
I don't lose.
安吉洛。
Angelo.
向唐 ・ 金。
Talk to Don King.
Dur á n 应该打一个。
Durán should fight no one but me.
该设置立即重赛。
Set the rematch immediately.
告诉你我要做什么 ， 卡洛斯。
Tell you what I'm gonna do, Carlos.
我会加入两个到八个及十个。
I'm gonna add a two to that eight and bring it up to ten.
$10 万 ， 卡洛斯。
$10 million, Carlos.
你有最高的战斗机的历史。
You're gonna have the highest paid fighter in history.
哦 ， 哦 ， 哦 ， 哦 ， 哦 ， 哦 ， 男孩。
Oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh, boy.
我知道你喜欢这种声音 ， 卡洛斯。
I know you like the sound of that, Carlos.
我知道你喜欢这种声音。
I know you like the sound of that.
EVA 。
Eva.
嘿 ， 丘洛。
Hey, Cholo.
好了。
Cholo.
我累坏了。
I'm exhausted.
嘿。
Hey.
我找了你一个星期。
I've been calling you for a week.
怎么了 ， eleta ？
What's up, Eleta?
- 我有好新闻好了。 -? que pas??
- I have great news, Cholo. - ?Que pasó?
他们要再来一次。
They want a rematch.
谁 ？
Who?
会是谁 ？ Leonard!
What do you mean who? Leonard!
Leonard? 他是一个受虐狂 ？
Leonard? What is he a masochist?
我曾给你最多的钱
I got you the most money ever
- 在一个次中量级。 - 多少钱 ？ 多少钱 ？
- for a welterweight. - How much? How much?
$8 万。
$8 million.
嘿 ， 波巴。
Hey, Boba.
800 万美元进行重赛。
$8 million for a rematch with me.
他一定是绝望。
He must be desperate.
不 ， 在。.. 不 ， 这个人需要钱。
No, the... no, the man needs the money.
- 好了。 好了。 - 什么 ？
- Cholo. Cholo. - What?
看着我。
Look at me.
注意。
Pay attention.
好 ， 好。
Okay, okay.
我去对付这些人。
I have to respond to these people tonight.
在证人面前 ， 接受着你 - 带 Leonard?
In front of witnesses, do you accept a rematch with-with Leonard?
我就打他 ， 但我不会嫁给一个男人 ， 他妈的。
I'd fight him, but I'm not gonna fucking marry a guy.
你喝酒。 你发福了。
You're drinking. You're getting fat.
你跑到我家来你叫我胖吗 ？
You come to my house and you call me fat?
你在你家里有镜子吗 ？
You have mirrors in your house?
你在发胖。
You're the one who's getting fat.
你在发胖的食物你吃过的
You're getting fat from all the food that you're eating
因为钱 ， 我给你。
because of the money that I'm making for you.
所以他妈的是什么 ？
So what the fuck?
寄生虫。
Parasite.
这就是你的 ， 你他妈的寄生虫。
That's what you are, you're a fucking parasite.
你叫我胖 ， 我打电话给你。
You call me fat, I call you parasite.
嘿 ， 嘿。 嘿 ， 嘿 ， eleta 。
Hey, hey. Hey, hey, Eleta.
现在你疯了吗 ？
Now you are mad?
嘿 ！
Hey!
你到底在干什么 ？
What the hell are you doing?
你没看见 ， 你让我们全身都湿了 ？
Can't you see you got us all wet?
你是一个他妈的寄生虫 ！
You are a fuckin' parasite too!
我告诉你离开你笨蛋 ！
I'm telling you to get out you idiot!
罗布 ， 你在干什么 ？
Rob, what are you doing?
他让我来浸泡。
He got me soaked.
我说出去 ！
Get out I said!
这是我他妈的房子 ， 蠢蛋。
This is my fuckin' house, you moron.
出去 ， 不然我就进去和你打破。
Get out or I'll get in and break you.
这是 chaflan ， 抢 ！
It's Chaflan, Rob!
停止它 ， 它就是 chaflan 。
Stop it, it's Chaflan.
那么 ， 丘洛 ？
Chivo, where's the Cholo?
好了 ！
Cholo!
这个男人 ， 和他说话。
That's the man, talk to him.
你还好吗 ？
How are you?
我在电视上看到你。
I saw you on TV.
我在城里 ， 唔。..
I was in town and, uh...
对自己说 ， “为什么不呢 ？”
said to myself, "Why not?"
嘿 ， 听着。 . 呃..
Hey, listen. Uh...
我不会为我做的事情。
I'm not proud of what I did.
但是看 ：
But look:
你是世界冠军。
you're the world champ.
她是 14 。
She was 14.
没有钱。
No money.
你的儿子。
Your son.
我在军队时。
I was in the army.
和 ， 呃 ， 当他们说你要离开 ，
And, uh, when they say you gotta leave,
没有什么如果但是。
there's no ifs or buts.
你想要什么 ？
What do you want?
没什么。
Nothing.
只是 ， 呃 ， 我想。
Just, uh, just thought I'd say hi.
Hi 。
Hi.
我以为你是美国人。
I thought you were American.
我是美国人。
I am American.
你看我到墨西哥。
You look Mexican to me.
嗯 ， 墨西哥后裔。
Well, Mexican heritage.
你以为我是 ， 嗯 ， 金发碧眼 ，
You thought I was, uh, blond,
蓝色的眼睛 ， 咦 ？ - 是的。
- blue eyes, eh? - Yes.
我不能我的过错。
I can't take back what I did.
我只能说 ， 嗯 ，
All I can say is, uh,
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
和我。..
And I'm...
我很骄傲你是我的儿子。
I'm proud that you're my son.
女士们 ， 先生们 ， 我给你带来拉斯维加斯演出。
Ladies and gentlemen, I bring you this show from Las Vegas.
不要错过这个国际对于巴拿马人。
Don't miss this international show for all Panamanians.
让我们玩一个游戏。 大家看球。..
Let's play a game. Everyone look at the ball...
停一下 ！
Hold it right there!
我饿了 ， 男人。
I'm hungry, man.
抓住他!
Catch him!
咸味。..
A bit salty...
但还是谢谢你。
but thank you.
令人作呕 ！
Revolting!
操你妈 ！
Fuck you!
当你在你的聚会。..
While you were at your party...
什么 ？
What?
chaflan 被杀。
Chaflan was killed.
谁告诉你 ？
Who told you?
你不能强迫他他做一些事情。
You can't discipline him by forcing him to do something.
你要让他住他的生命。
You have to let him live his life in a certain way.
震惊!
Stunned!
我被惊呆了 ！
I was stunned!
他眩晕 ， 他听见你。
And he will be stunned when he hears what you did.
我向他解释此事。
And I have to explain it to him.
是啊 ， 我向他解释了他 800 万美元 ，
Yeah, explain to him that I got him $8 million,
- 这是最赚钱的.. - 他不喜欢。
- which is the most money... - He doesn't care.
-. ..that 任何人。 - 但他甚至都不知道。
- ...that anyone has ever made. - But he doesn't even know that.
他不知道 ， 甚至为自己。
He doesn't know that even for himself.
钱是最重要的事情。
That the money is the least important thing.
他是个职业拳击手。 他可以减肥。
He's a professional fighter. He can lose that weight.
三个月减掉 40 磅。
Three months to lose almost 40 pounds.
你知道 ， 做为战斗机 ？
You know what that does to a fighter?
我为他着想。
I want what's best for him.
- 我想我们做什么对他最好。 - 这不是最好的他。
- I want us to do what is best for him. - That's not best for him.
最适合你但不适合他。
That's best for you but not for him.
嗯 ， 这是你的意见。
Well, that's your opinion.
让我告诉你这个。..
Let me tell you this...
那不是我的意见。 这是一个事实。
That's not my opinion. That's a fact.
如果他不参加这场比赛 ， 你知道的
If he doesn't take this fight, you know what's
不会再发生 ？ 他要去打一些无足轻重的人。
going to end up happening? He's going to go fight some nobody.
他要和他永远不会失去 ， 在一万年前 ，
He's going to lose and he will never, in a million years,
接近使钱他现在做的。
get close to making the money he's making right now.
他 Dur á n 。 他不会输的。
He's Durán. He can't lose.
他 Dur á n 。 当他 ， 他不能输给一个无名小卒。
He's Durán. When he is focused, he doesn't lose to a nobody.
你知道的。
You know that.
他赢了。
He won.
让他欣赏它。 他让党。
Let him enjoy it. Let him party.
如果他参加聚会 ？
So what if he's partying?
如果他吃吗 ？
So what if he's eating?
让他吃。 让他玩得很开心。
Let him eat. Let him have a good time.
他从未做过任何事情。 他从来不吃任何东西。
He never had anything. He never ate anything.
而现在 ， 他终于做了点。
And now he's finally earned something.
他自己挣的。
He's earned it himself.
没有人给他。 而你只是把它拿走。
Nobody gave it to him. And you just take it away.
我曾经处理过的动物。
I've been dealing with that animal for the last ten years.
他的、他的、他的 ， 他是个好孩子 ， 一学就会
He's a, he's a, he's a, he's a good kid...
他需要被惩戒 ！
He needs to be disciplined!
他将被惩处 ！ 这是我的工作。
He will be disciplined! That's my job.
如果他输了 ， 我们可以和另一复赛。..
If he loses, then we can sign another rematch and...
你想要你的病态 paskudnyak 失去战机。
You're a sick paskudnyak wanting your fighter to lose.
不 ， 我是说 ， “如果” 。..
No, what I said was, "if"...
- 卡洛斯 ， 有你的钱。 射线。
- Carlos, you have the money. - Ray.
- 家有钱。 线。
- Family has the money. - Ray.
他没有拥有它。 他不关心。
He didn't have it. He doesn't care.
最重要的胜利。
The most important thing for him is to win.
对我来说最重要的是要赢。
The most important thing for me is to win.
为了赢得尊重。
To have the respect of winning.
右。 我是说 ， 如果输了 ， 他再比一场。..
Right. What I said was, if he loses, he can have a rematch...
我完成了。
I'm done.
见到父亲。
I met my father.
- 你呢 ？ - MM - HMM 。
- Did you? - Mm-hmm.
他是个什么样的人 ？
What was he like?
他是墨西哥人。
He's Mexican.
我以为你说他是美国人。
I thought you said he was American.
嗯 ， 他是美国人。
Um, he's American.
我是说 ， 他出生在美国。
I mean, he was born in America.
我想他会像保罗 ・ 纽曼。
And I thought that he would look like Paul Newman.
但他看上去更像私人别墅。
But he looks more like Pancho Villa.
你认为长得像保罗纽曼吗 ？
Think you look like Paul Newman?
没有 ， 但是 ， 这次也许。
No, but Charles Bronson, maybe.
有其他人你必须学会原谅。
There's someone else you're going to have to learn to forgive.
卡洛斯。
Carlos.
为什么呢 ？
Why?
他同意重赛。
He agreed to the rematch.
什么时候 ？
For when?
- 再过三个月。 - 这不可能。
- Three months from now. - Well, that's impossible.
我们要让它成为可能。 他已经签署。
We have to make it possible. He already signed.
他不能没有我的允许。
He can't sign without my permission.
他说你给他你的许可。
He said you gave him your permission.
在你的房子 ， 在一次聚会。
At your house, at a party.
在众人面前。
In front of a lot of people.
目击者 ， 他说。
Witnesses, he said.
嗨 ！
Hi!
Hi 。 他们投保。
Hi. They're insured.
所以如果你能消灭他们。
So you can destroy them if you want.
不管怎么样 ， 你要做的斗争。
No matter what, you're going to do the fight.
- 你要我叫警察吗 ？ - 是啊 ， 叫警察 ！
- You want me to call the police? - Yeah, call the police!
他们把我关进监狱而你失去了你失去了你他妈的..
They put me in jail and you lose... you lose your fucking
$8 万 ！
$8 million!
好 ， 现在好了 ， 现在你知道这只是生意。
Well, now, Cholo, now you understand it's a business.
- 我不是妓女 ！ - 廉价妓女
- I'm not a hooker! - A hooker is cheaper
而且它不能创造这么多的问题。
and it doesn't create this much problems.
你现在应该被训练。
You should be training right now.
我所有我的生活 ！
I've been training all my fucking life!
回家吧 ， 罗伯特。
Go home, Roberto.
如果你输掉了这场战争 ， 我们再比一场。
If you lose the fight, we can have a rematch.
我不会输 ！
I don't lose!
在巴拿马 ， 民族主义者的示威。..
In Panama, a nationalist demonstration...
我们得到了 75 天减掉 35 磅。
We got 75 days to lose 35 pounds.
你得继续工作 ， 好了。
You've got to keep working, Cholo.
我不想这么做 ， 老兄 ， 我想休息。
I don't want to do this, man, I want to rest.
- 你想休息吗 ？ - 我很累 ， 男人。
- You want to rest? - I'm tired, man.
- 你想休息吗 ？ - 是的。
- You want to rest? - Yes.
休息是生锈。 和你知道的。
To rest is to rust. And you know that.
你对这样的战士 ， 要警惕
You're the kind of fighter that's gotta stay on your toes
如果你不警惕 ， 然后你就失业了 ， 就这样。
and if you don't stay on your toes, then you're gone, that's it.
你可以这样做。
And you can do this.
但你必须做这个决定。
But you're going to have to decide to do this.
没有人可以代替你。
Nobody can do it for you.
没有任何一种不情愿的英雄。
There's no such thing as a reluctant hero.
你必须自己干。
You're going to have to do it on your own.
我工作了一辈子 ， 男人。
I work all my life, man.
我一生都工作。
I work all my life.
我没有带任何食物 ， 当我还是个孩子。
I didn't have any food when I was a kid.
我很饿 ， 我饿了。
I'm hungry, man, I'm hungry.
我不想要到饿了。
I don't want to be hungry anymore.
我想做我 ， 雷。
I want to enjoy what I have, Ray.
对 ， 有点出乎意料。
The rioting that followed was unexpected.
中区警察使用催泪瓦斯和消防龙头 ， 驱散示威者。
The Zone police used tear gas and fire hoses to drive off the demonstrators.
我理解这一点。
I understand that.
我可以设法说服国王并延迟战斗。
I can try to convince Don King to delay the fight.
但我们必须随时准备在情况下您必须战斗。
But we got to be ready to fight in case you have to.
好吧。
Okay.
你还生气吗 ？
You still mad?
不知道怎么告诉你。
Don't know what to tell you.
原谅我吗 ？
Forgive me?
好吧。
Okay.
我需要你。
I need you.
我不打了。
I don't want to fight.
专注于你的训练。
Focus on your training.
你要和我的孩子吗 ？
Why don't you come with the kids?
我不想见到你。
I wanna see you.
你需要休息 ， 罗伯特。 去睡觉吧。
You need to rest, Robert. Go to sleep.
爱你。
Love you.
我喜欢你。
I love you.
我也是。
Me too.
你知道我是黑人 ？
Do you realize I'm black?
你知道我是只黑色的启动子
Do you realize that I am the only black promoter
在商界 ， 如果你拔、
in the business and that if you pull out,
- 他们会炒我吗 ？ - 我们不会撤出。
- they will fry me? - We're not pulling out.
他不能把体重降下来。
He can't make the weight.
他不可能犯那么大的重量。
It's impossible for him to make the weight.
我们得到了 CBS 。 我们到体育场了。
We got CBS. We got the stadium.
我们的赞助商。 我们买到了票。
We got the sponsors. We got the tickets.
你不能去叫他们吗 ？
You can't go to them and ask them?
是啊 ， 我可以去问一问。
Yeah, I can go to them and ask them.
我就说 ， “对不起 ， 先生 ， 我需要一个月。”
I'll say, "Excuse me, Mr. CBS, I need another month."
他们会说 ， “黑鬼黑 ， 没有。”
They'll say, "Black nigger, no."
有什么事故发生。
That's what's going to happen.
你儿子有让他或他的重量将被取消资格。
Your boy either has to make his weight or he will be disqualified, period.
是啊 ， 但你让它自己。
Yeah, but you're making it about yourself.
你不会再约阿鲁姆。
You're making it about Bob Arum.
你是说 ， “我会看起来很糟。
You're saying that "I'm gonna look bad.
我只有黑色的启动子。 “
I'm the only black promoter."
恕我直言 ， 这并不意味着什么。
With all due respect, that doesn't mean anything.
你有责任。
You have a responsibility to boxing.
拳击吗 ？
Boxing?
拳击一直是被罪犯和强盗
Boxing has been run by gangsters and criminals
流氓无赖的那天起它就诞生了。
and scoundrels since the day it was born.
来吧 ， 现在。 你不要把责任推给我。
Come on, now. Don't you put this on me.
- 不要你敢推我头上。 - 这是个草率的生产
- Don't you dare put this on me. - It's a sloppy production
所以当他一开始也没做好。
to start so soon when he's not ready.
我反而认为 ， Roberto Dur á n ， 男子手中的石头 ，
I happen to think that Roberto Durán, the man with the hands of stone,
如果你向他挑战 ， 他将准备。
if you challenge him, he will be ready.
他在巴拿马的精神在他的心脏。
He has got the spirit of Panama in his heart.
你不用告诉我他有什么。
You don't have to tell me what he has.
我知道这里有人比他更好。
I know him better than anybody here.
好吧 ， 我很抱歉。
All right, I'm sorry.
如果我们继续这样下去 ，
If we continue down this road, Ray,
我就告你违反合约。
I'm gonna have to sue you for breach of contract.
这是你让我们陷入一些混乱。
This is some mess you got us into.
哦。 天啊 ， 雷 ， 你吓死我了。
Oh. Gosh, Ray, you scared me.
你在这里干什么 ？
What are you doing here?
你是怎么进来的 ？
How did you even get in?
嘿。 . 什么..
Hey. What...
. 嘿..
Hey...
雷 ， 我们不能这样做。
Ray, we can't do this.
宝贝 ， 宝贝 ， 好吧 ， 来吧。
Babe, baby, okay, come on.
雷 ， 瞧 ， 这是犯规。
Ray, look, it's against the rules.
战斗就在拐角处。
The fight's just around the corner.
来吧 ， 来吧 ， 宝贝。
Come on, come on, babe.
不 ， 不 ， 不 ， 不 ， 不。
No, no, no, no, no.
嘘 ， 嘘 ， 嘘 ， 嘘。
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
这是我的规则。
It's my rules this time.
好吗 ？
Okay?
你要打败 Dur á n,
You want to beat Durán,
你要羞辱他。
you're going to have to humiliate him.
你去给他丢脸了 ， 在大家面前。
You're going to have to shame him, right there, in front of everyone.
它不会工作。
It's not going to work.
对不起。
Sorry.
对不起 ， 你必须捍卫冠军。
Sorry, you have to defend the title.
或者他们会做什么 ， 他们就会把它拿走。
Or what they'll do is they'll just take it away.
- 什么 ？ - 将所述带。
- What? - They will take away the belt.
但我赢得了比赛。
But I won the fight.
大家都看到了。
Everybody saw it.
他们可以拿走我的皮带吗 ？
They can just take away my belt?
他们 - 他们了 ， 他们能做的。
They-they... that's what they can do.
他们会拿走你不捍卫它。
They will take it away if you don't defend it.
Roberto Dur á n 把我们带到了一个新的黄金时代的拳击。
Roberto Durán had brought us a new golden era for boxing.
然而 ， 我们提醒他 ， 他的作品。
Yet here we were, reminding him that he didn't matter.
这决定了后面的房间
That decisions were made in the back room
当时他只有马戏团的动物需要的门票销售。
and he was only a circus animal we needed for ticket sales.
批准。
Approved.
你会看到在这个斗争。
You're going to see blood in this fight.
我不喜欢小丑。
I don't like clowns.
当你走进了斗牛圈 ， 你是来打架的 ， 不是舞蹈或小丑。
When you come into the ring, you come to fight, not to dance or to clown.
他一直在模仿阿里 ， 他一直如此。
He's imitating Ali all the time, that's what he does.
他没有任何风格。
He doesn't have any style.
我把你一把他的模仿者是输家。
I'm going to knock you out, 'cause imitators are losers.
我不喜欢你。
And I don't like you.
嗯 ， 我觉得 Dur á n 是一个可爱的家伙。
Well, I think Durán is a lovable guy.
我想要我的儿子像他一样。
And I want my son to be just like him.
听着。
Listen.
我认为 Dur á n 是坚韧的
I think Durán is a tough,
令人印象深刻 ， 智能战斗机。
impressive, intelligent fighter.
我们是一个重大打击。
And we are in for a serious fight.
你会觉得不好。
You're gonna feel bad.
停止它。
Stop it.
- 递给我。 - 你不能再这么吃下去。
- Hand me that. - You can't eat like this.
递给我黄色的东西。
Pass me that yellow thing.
我为什么没有翅膀 ？ 我问道。
Why didn't I get wings when I asked?
你有很多。
You have plenty.
以及为什么你看着 Leonard?
And why were you looking at Leonard?
不要说这个。
Don't start with that.
你以为我没看见你 ？
You think I didn't see you?
不要愚弄我。
Don't fool me.
- 你以为我傻啊 ？ - 你是疯了。
- You think I'm stupid? - Insane is what you are.
我看到他在跟你使眼色。
I saw him winking at you.
和所有你的微笑。
And you were all smiles.
这位前世界冠军
The former champion of the world,
Sugar Ray Leonard!
..will 。被进行复赛。
...will be the rematch of the century.
这里 ， 带着随从来到伦纳德 Angelo Dundee LED 。
Here comes Leonard with his entourage led by Angelo Dundee.
这就是他 ， 今晚的挑战者 ， 莱纳德。
And here he is, the challenger tonight, Sugar Ray Leonard.
看起来很沉稳。
Looks very composed.
他看起来非常放松。
He looks very relaxed.
..world 。 ！
...world!
罗伯托。..
Roberto...
Dur á n!
Durán!
该男子用手中的石头 ，
The man with the hands of stone,
巴拿马的
from Panama, has to be regarded
作为最伟大的战士。
as one of the greatest fighters of all time.
现在 ， 雷 ・ 查尔斯 ， 在荣誉的人
And now Ray Charles, in honor of whom
Sugar Ray Leonard Charles 受洗
Sugar Ray Charles Leonard was baptized,
将演唱 “美丽美国” 。
will sing "America the Beautiful."
美哉
O beautiful
紫金山天文台的。..
For purple mountain...
美国
America
美国甜
Sweet America
他脱下他的恩典
He done shed His grace
你应该和他的爱
And you oughta love Him for it
因为他。..
'Cause He...
从大海到。..
From sea to...
外面去游泳 ！
Get out there and swim!
彼岸。..
Shining sea...
谢谢你 ， 雷。
Thank you, Ray.
踢他的屁股 ， 儿子。
Kick his ass, son.
- 噢 ， 我会的。 - 为了我。
- Oh, I will. - Do it for me.
在开始行动。
The action begins.
伦纳德的傲慢 ，
Leonard fighting for pride tonight,
虽然 Dur á n 在捍卫他的不朽。
while Durán defends his place in immortality.
Dur á n! Dur á n! Dur á n!
Durán! Durán! Durán!
Dur á n! Dur á n!
Durán! Durán!
还有伦纳德。
There's Leonard.
这就是他想做的。
That's what he wants to do in this fight.
他说他不在他的刺拳有效地工作。
He says he did not work his jab efficiently in the first fight.
不要跟着他 ！
Stop following him!
去追他 ！
Go after him!
抓住他 ！ 抓住他 ！ 之后他 ！
Get him! Get him! After him!
我们有 20 秒。
We have 20 seconds left in the round.
他窒息。
Suffocate him.
在绳索 ！ 决不手软 ！
Up against the ropes! No mercy!
在绳索 ！
Up against the ropes!
打断他的话。 让他靠在围绳上。
Cut him off. Get him up against the ropes.
被绳索 ！
Against the ropes!
这是一个更加自信的莱昂纳德
This is a much more confident Leonard
我们今晚在这里看到。
we are seeing here tonight.
你们必须是主机。 你就像一个客人。
You gotta be the host. You're acting like a guest.
你得给他压力 ， 你应该把他的绳索。
You gotta pressure him, you gotta put him on the ropes.
你必须马上到主体。
You gotta bang to the body.
这是你的房子。 不是别人的。 这是你的房子。
It's your house. Nobody else's. It's your house.
- 你明白吗 ， 丘洛 ？ - 我感觉很不舒服。
- You understand that, Cholo? - I don't feel good.
你让这家伙从你。
You're letting this guy run all over you.
他在你身边。
He's running in circles around you.
- 你知道他 ， 他的防御。 - 我感觉很不舒服。
- You know that he does, that's his defense. - I don't feel good.
你不觉得吗 ？ 你吃的太多了。
You don't feel good? You ate too much.
聚焦。 别让这家伙跑了。
Focus. Don't let this guy run on you.
别让他跑 ， 别让他跑了。
Don't let him run, don't let him run on you.
- Dur á n 和下跌得更多 ， 他的.. - 把他留在那里 ， 把他留在那里 ！
- Durán is falling more and more, on his part... - Keep him there, keep him there!
..into 。谁先谁后的第一次战斗。
...into the pattern of the first fight.
- Dur á n 在第一枪。 - 是啊 ！
- Durán got in a good shot. - Yeah!
- 这是什么 Dur á n 。 - 就这样就这样 ， 好了。
- This is what Durán can do. - That's it, that's it, Cholo.
嘿 ！
Hey!
Dur á n Leonard 正在努力控制。
Durán is struggling to contain Leonard.
你可以看到他的愤怒和不满。
You can see his anger and frustration.
截住他!
Cut him off!
伦纳德是一个移动的目标。
Leonard is a moving target.
- Dur á n 和是。.. - 你们抓到他了 ！
- And Durán is going... - You get him!
约束自己。 看着我 ！ 看着我 ！
Get control of yourself. Look at me! Look at me!
- 盒子 ， 混蛋 ！ - 听着。
- Box, motherfucker! - Listen.
- 你要打他。 - 不要。
- You gotta box him. - Don't.
- 你让他这么做。 - 我很生气他妈的。
- You're letting him do that. - I'm very fucking pissed.
Dur á n 无法把他拉起来的绳子在他的第一次战斗。
Durán cannot get him up against the ropes like he did in the first fight.
看到你的尺寸吗 ？
Have you seen the size of the ring?
他们修建了环的目的 ， 这样他就能摆脱我。
They built the ring on purpose so he can escape from me.
是在嘲笑他。
The sneer is off his face.
是的 ！ 是的 ， 雷 ！
Yes! Yes, Ray!
不 ， 不 ， 我是一名拳击手。 我不是他妈的芭蕾舞。..
No, no, I'm a boxer. I'm not a fucking ballerina...
我不是来这里跳舞的人。
I don't come here to dance with a man.
他与 Dur á n 。 公开。
And he's got Durán. Openly.
不只是愤怒 ， 而是困惑。
Not just furious but puzzled.
Dur á n 运动造成了困扰。
Durán troubled by the movement.
邓迪最好建议 ， 我认为 ， 告诉 Leonard 停止。
Dundee would be well advised, I think, to tell Leonard to stop that.
Leonard 卖弄技巧。
Leonard flaunting his skills.
- 这是个截然不同的人。.. - 别跟他走 ！
- And it is a vastly different human being... - Stop following him around!
..that. Dur á n 是今晚。
...that Durán is tonight.
是的 ， 宝贝 ！
That's right, baby!
是啊 ！
Yeah!
对身体 ， 然后到头部。
Work on the body and then up to the head.
- 大家都在笑我。 - 没有。
- Everybody is laughing at me. - No.
你的头。
Get out of your head.
- 我不是他妈的小丑在中、上环。 - 拿 ， 拿了你的。..
- I'm not a fucking clown in the, on the ring. - Get, get out of your...
他发现他的左 ！
And he caught him with the left!
是的。
Yes.
冷静下来。
Calm down.
- 你让。.. - 我到处找那混蛋。
- You're let... - I'm chasing the motherfucker.
你让。.. L - 看着我。
You're let... L-Look at me.
你不需要这样做 ， 好吗 ？
You don't need to do that, all right?
你想成为次中量级世界冠军。
You're about to be welterweight champion of the world.
你的头 ！
Get out of your head!
你没有做你该做什么。
You're not doing what you should be doing.
你知道怎么做 ， 走出去。
You know how to do it, get out there.
我想成为你的骄傲。 我想告诉你我想要你到。..
I want to be proud of you. I want you to get out there and I want you to...
看着我 ！ 你 Roberto Dur á n 。
Look at me! You're Roberto Durán.
在此同时 ， 无影。
Get in there and act like him.
去的身体 ！ 截住他!
Go to the body! Cut him off!
嘿。
Hey.
丘洛 ， 你在干什么 ？
Cholo, what are you doing?
你在干什么 ？
What are you doing?
他的辞职 … 他 ！
He... he quit!
Dur á n! 他说 ， “No m á s.”
Durán quit! He said, "no más."
不 ， 不 ， 不 ， 不 ， 不 ， 不。 好了。
No, no, no, no, no, no. Cholo.
Roberto Dur á n 已经辞职。
Roberto Durán has quit.
你在干什么 ？ 你。.. 你不能.
What are you doing? You're going... you can't.
你在干什么 ？
The heck are you doing?
- 你打他。 - 没有。 他妈的他。
- You got to fight him. - No. Fuck him.
- 你必须打他 ！ - 不 ， 不 ， 他是一个失败者。..
- You've gotta fight him! - No, no, he's a loser...
你不能。 你。..
You can't. You've got to...
- 你也是。.. 你在做什么吗 ， 丘洛 ？ - 我不会打架。
- Are you... What are you doing, Cholo? - I'm not going to fight.
我不是来打架的小丑。
I didn't come here to fight a clown.
- 你得去战斗。 - 不 ， 不 ， 不 ， 不 ， 不。
- You gotta go fight. - No, no, no, no, no.
他们他妈的我。
They fuck me over.
- 我受够了。 - 不 ， 不 ！
- I've had enough. - No, no!
我不是一个小丑。
I'm not a clown.
听着 ， 你去在那里了。
Listen, you have to go in there and fight.
你不能这样做。
You can't do this.
- 你为什么这么做 ？ - 这是废话。
- Why are you doing this? - It's fucking bullshit.
罗伯托。 罗伯特 ， 怎么回事 ？
Roberto. Roberto, what happened?
我退出拳击比赛。
I'm retiring from boxing.
他说 ， 他退出拳击比赛。
He, he said he's retiring from boxing.
突然 ， 莫名其妙 ，
Suddenly, inexplicably,
战斗已经结束。
the fight has ended.
不要, Robbie!
Don't do it, Robbie!
战斗 ！
Fight!
你必须战斗 ！
You have to fight!
胡说。
Bullshit.
这就是美国。
This is for America.
我们成功了 ！ 我们成功了 ！
We did it! We did it!
去。
Go.
我不在乎有多少能力你是一个战士。
I don't care how much ability you've got as a fighter.
如果你认为 ， 你只是个流浪汉在公园。
If you can't think, you're just another bum in the park.
拳击是大脑而不是肌肉。
Boxing is brain over brawn.
成千上万的人在超级圆顶体育馆
Thousands of people in the Super Dome
而在全美院线大规模关闭电路
and millions more in the closed circuit theaters across the country
自己被骗去看看 ， 让他们看到报酬。
have been cheated out of a fight that they paid to see.
委员会和公众应该得到解释。
The commission and the public deserve an explanation.
当一个战士在战斗中失去的环 ， 它经常被飞机上的故障。
When a fighter loses a fight in the ring, it oftentimes is the fighter's fault.
但当一个战士在战斗中失去了他的头 ，
But when a fighter loses a fight in his head,
常常是教练的错。
it always is the trainer's fault.
该摄像机。 在闪烁。
The cameras. The flashes.
麦克风。
The microphones.
... 英雄的地方。
The... hero worshipers.
电视会让别人认为自己是一个神。
Television can make anyone think of himself as a god.
和我。..
And I...
也许我不能 ， 呃 ，
I probably failed at, uh,
我战机停飞。
keeping my fighter grounded.
但我可以告诉你 ：
But I can tell you this:
Roberto Dur á n 绝不是懦夫。
Roberto Durán is no coward.
他没有离开这个圈不再惧怕的对手。
He did not leave the ring out of fear of an opponent.
他离开它的骄傲。
He left it out of pride.
有说法是暂停 Dur á n 。
There is talk of suspending Durán.
你说怎么样 ？
What would you say about that?
我 - 我不知道发生了什么事。
I-I don't know what happened.
如果不的话 ， 那么你就不。
And if I don't, then you don't.
但是我知道
But what I do know is
Dur á n Roberto 如何开始人生。
how Roberto Durán began in life.
我知道他自己的意志。
I know what he willed himself to become.
我深知荣誉的他 ，
I know the honor he has brought this business,
有时 ， 不值得。
which sometimes doesn't deserve it.
我知道 ， 你不能停学。
And I know you cannot suspend him.
他值得更好的。
He deserves better.
如果你不明白 ， 你对他做这些 ，
And if you don't understand that and you do this to him,
你明天醒来 ， 你会感到羞愧。
you will wake up tomorrow and you will feel ashamed.
快, 快!
Faster, faster!
让孩子们在那里 ！
Get in there kids!
你怎么了 ？
What's wrong with you?
操你妈 ！
Fuck you all!
我们有理由或者没有权利
We have no more right or reason
出卖了巴拿马运河区 ， 会比我们现在放弃阿拉斯加。
for giving away the Panama Canal Zone than we would to now give away Alaska.
我认为 ， 我们的政策应该是一个外国
And I think that our foreign policy should be one
我们和他们自己的渠道 ， 应该说我们的政府 ，
and we, the people who own the Canal, should say to our government,
瞧 ， 先生 ， 我们建造东西 ， 托里霍斯。
look, tell Mr. Torrijos that we built that thing.
我们买了这个地方。 我们付的钱。
We bought the place. We paid for it.
我们打算把它从这里开始了。
And we intend to keep it from here on out.
到这里来。
Come up here.
起床。
Get up.
过来。
Come.
让我们离开这里。
Let's get out of here.
这不是生活。
This is not life.
它的真实生活。
It's real life.
你丈夫骗了。
Your husband got fucked.
大家都说他是一个失败者。
And everyone calls him a loser.
证明他们错了。
Show them wrong.
为什么呢 ？
Why?
为了钱吗 ？
For money?
巴拿马的荣耀吗 ？
For the glory of Panama?
跟这个国家的伪君子。
To hell with this nation of hypocrites.
嗯 ？
Huh?
如果是这样 ， 我们就像你喊停 ？
If life is such shit, why don't we stop it like you stopped the fight?
不 ！ 不 ！
No! No!
好了 ！ 不 ！ 不 ！
Cholo! No! No!
我完成了。
I'm done.
去找别的女人。
Go find another woman.
我可以有成千上万的妇女。
I can have thousands of women.
我的孩子。
I'm taking the kids.
有点距离, 但是孩子们会住在这里。
Go to hell, but the kids stay here.
我离开我的孩子 ！
I'm leaving with my kids!
孩子们是我的。
The kids are mine.
什么 ？
What?
说话 ！
Speak for God's sake!
托里霍斯总统被杀。
President Torrijos was killed.
好了 ！
Cholo!
在拳击比赛 ， 我就杀了你。
Get in the ring and I'll kill you.
一起吃午餐吧 ， 孩子。
Come have lunch with us, kid.
我不需要你的食物。
I don't need your food.
我赚我的饭。
I earn my meals fighting.
你会祈求我的亲笔签名。
You'll soon be begging for my autograph.
说得好 ， 冠军。
Well said, champ.
谁说说 ？
Who says well said?
你不是来自 EL chorrillo 。 “刺青不 ： sshit 从你。
You are not from El Chorrillo anymore. "No Mas: sshit from you.
我送你去太平间 ， 让你退出了 ！
I'll send you to the morgue and make you quit again!
忘恩负义的孩子。
Ungrateful kid.
它永远不会满足。
It's never enough!
托里霍斯领导这个国家不就去吃屎。
Without Torrijos' leadership this country will go to shit.
咱们回家吧 ， 罗伯特。
Let's go home, Robert.
他们是对的。
They are right.
所希望的 EL chorrillo 走开了。
The hope of El Chorrillo walked away.
我离开了斗殴。
I walked away from the fight.
我走了就像我的父亲。
I walked away just like my father.
是啊 ！
Yeah!
我让他们失望。
I let them down.
我让他们失望了 ， 我让你失望。
I let them down and I let you down.
我不需要这个冠军 ， 但我需要去参与战斗。
I don't need to be the champion, but I need to fight.
我去打仗。
I'm going to fight.
我要你训练我 ， 爸爸。 请不要说不。
I need you to train me, Dad. Please don't say no.
我很抱歉。 我已经退休了。
I'm sorry. I'm retired.
我不能。
I can't.
你是我父亲 ， 男人。
You're my father, man.
你是唯一一个我。
You're the only one I have.
听着。 我 - 我不能。
Listen. I-I can't.
我 - 我不干了。
I-I'm done with it.
而这与你无关。
And it has nothing to do with you.
我们谈论我。 我老了。 我很累。
We're talking about me now. I'm old. I'm tired.
你不需要我。
You don't need me.
你从来没有真正做。
You never really did.
你是一个伟大的自然斗士。
You're a naturally great fighter.
你有伟大的本能。
You have great fighter's instincts.
我只是在那里支持你。
I was just there to support you.
那不是真的。
That's not true.
我需要你在我这边 ， 雷。
I need you in my corner, Ray.
不 ， 你没有。 你是成年人了。
Not anymore, you don't. You're an adult now.
你有你自己的孩子。
You have children of your own.
你不需要一个父亲。
You don't need a father.
你需要有人带你回到街上。
You need somebody to bring the street back into you.
- 跟 plomo 。 - plomo ？
- Talk to Plomo. - Plomo?
他知道你比任何人都清楚。
He knows you better than anybody.
他一直跟着你。
He's been with you from the beginning.
我再帮你打。
I'll help you get a fight.
我会看着你所有的时间。
I'll be watching you all the time.
但 plomo 把你带回去。
But get Plomo to bring you back.
你需要。
That's who you need.
- 好吧。 - 请 ， 永远记住。
- Okay. - And please, always remember.
在美国 ， 你说话了吗 ？
The American you're talking to now?
他给了你最好的年头。
He gave you the best years of his life.
笨蛋。
Schmuck.
你没有理由感到内疚。
You have no reason to feel guilty here.
嗯 ， 他是我的拳手 ， 。..
Well, he's my fighter, so...
哦。..
Yeah, well...
你需要找到最佳。
You need to do what you think is best for everyone.
你认为什么最好 ？
What do you think is best?
那要看情况了。
It depends.
你认为他是一个 ， 你现在最需要的 ？
You think that he's the one that needs you the most right now?
他准备复出 ， 首先是用 plomo Dur á n
To prepare him for his comeback, the first thing Plomo did was take Durán
在巴拿马的灵心。..
to the spiritual heart of Panama...
..the 。游行的黑色基督的波托韦洛。
...the procession of the Black Christ of Portobelo.
plomo Dur á n 答应当他还是个孩子
Plomo had promised Durán when he was a kid
如果他出轨了 ， 他要带他回监狱。
that if he went off track, he'd take him back to jail.
他确实这么做了。
So he did.
我赚了很多钱在战斗。
I made a lot of money on that fight.
无论你需要什么 ， 答案已经是肯定的。
Whatever you need, the answer's already yes.
罗伯托 - Dur á n 。 - 他妈的没有。
- Roberto Durán. - Fuck no.
他是个坏消息 ， 雷。
He's bad news, Ray.
你可以做得更好。
You can do better than that bum.
他需要回归。
He needs a comeback.
他辞职。
He quit.
明白吗 ？ 你不能那么做。
Understand? You can't do that.
除非你告诉我们。
Unless we tell you to.
No m á s.
No más.
No m á s, my ass.
No más, my ass.
没有人会花钱去看 ， 窗明几净。
Nobody's gonna pay to see that spick.
Moore 戴维怎么样 ？
How about Davey Moore?
戴维摩尔 ？
Davey Moore?
我的意思是 ， 他 24 岁的怪物。
I mean, he's a 24-year-old monster.
你会杀死 Dur á n 。
You'll get Durán killed.
那不是大家都想看
Isn't that what everybody wants to see
之后他在新奥尔良吗 ？ - 也许。
- after what he did in New Orleans? - Maybe.
我绝对会花钱去看 Dur á n get a beating.
I certainly would pay to see Durán get a beating.
- 我会考虑的。 - 好吧。
- I'll think about it. - Okay.
我想它。
I'm gonna think about it.
你是世界上最好的拳手。
You were the best fighter in the world.
我想看见的。
And I want to see that back in the ring.
你真的很开心 ， 那将是另一个黑家伙揍今晚。
You're just happy it will be another black guy getting punched tonight.
没有狗屎。
No shit.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
是啊 ， 男人。
Yeah, man.
告诉你妻子。..
And tell your wife...
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
我会的。
I will.
好吧 ， 今晚是
Well, tonight happens to be
Roberto Dur á n 的 32 岁生日当天 ， 他承诺要把
Roberto Durán's 32nd birthday, and he's promised to turn
麦迪逊广场花园的战斗到为他和他的朋友。
Madison Square Garden's fight into a party for he and his friends.
- 是不是雷? - 你怎么想 ？
- Did Ray come? - Why are you thinking about Ray?
莱纳德我给你报告代表 CBS 体育。
I am Sugar Ray Leonard reporting to you on behalf of CBS Sports.
雷 ， 你知道我尊重你的对手 ，
Ray, I know you respect your former rival,
但看看他结束这一个连。
but let's see if he even finishes this one.
但 Dur á n 的体验一定会玩
But Durán's experience is sure to play
在今晚的战斗。
a great deal in the fight tonight.
他一开始是轻量级的 ， 结果现在战斗为轻中量级。
He started out as a lightweight, and now he's fighting as a light middleweight.
现在 ， 这是一个巨大的跳跃。
Now, that's a tremendous jump for any fighter.
好吧 ， 我给你的指令在更衣室里。
Okay, I gave both of you instructions in the dressing room.
我想提醒你。
I want to remind you.
服从我的命令。
Obey my commands at all times.
他年轻、强壮 ， 有的达到 ，
He is younger, stronger, with a far longer reach,
但我可以告诉你的首先 ， 右和左手经验
but I can tell you from first, right and left hand experience
为什么他们叫 manos de Piedra 手中的石头。
why they call Manos de Piedra Hands of Stone.
他在右边路 ， Dur á n 和感觉它。
Moore has power in that right, and Durán felt it.
摩尔希望 Dur á n ！
Moore wants to get Durán out of here!
Dur á n 可以承受惩罚他吗 ？
Can Durán withstand the punishment he's taking?
我们可以看到 ， Roberto Dur á n 。
We could be seeing the end of Roberto Durán.
Dur á n 的攻击。 他将在所有。
Durán is on the attack. He is going all in.
如此巨大的风险 ， 这对年轻的摩尔 ？
How big a risk is this against the younger Moore?
你感觉怎么样 ？
How are you feeling?
我想把这些手套杀了他 ！
I wanna take these gloves off and kill him!
这样做就对了
That's the way to do it.
没有怜悯。
No mercy.
聚焦在他身上。
Focus on him.
他就是你的了。 他已经死了。
He's yours. He's already dead.
呼吸。..
Breathe...
这就是它。 让我们去。
That's it. Let's go.
我喜欢你。
I love you.
你知道有多少。
You know how much.
你是我的儿子。
You are my son.
你是我的英雄。
You are my hero.
Dur á n! Dur á n! Dur á n! Dur á n!
Durán! Durán! Durán! Durán!
Dur á n 已经找到了家的感觉 ， 用右手 ！
Durán has found a home for that right hand!
他着陆了。
He's landing it now.
还有毛巾!
And there's the towel!
Roberto Dur á n 是新的
Roberto Durán is the new
世界超级次中量级世界冠军 ！
super welterweight champion of the world!
他的生日。
And it's his birthday.
你回来我的爱。
You're back, my love.
雷 ！
Ray!
生日快乐 ， 爸爸 ！ 生日快乐 ， 爸爸 ！
Happy birthday, Papa! Happy birthday, Papa!
生日快乐 ！
Happy birthday!
是啊 ！ 谢谢你 ！
Yeah! Thank you!